Alban: It is so stinking nice to
like, show up and record this
show. And Travis has already put
together an outline. Kevin's got
suggestions, I throw my thoughts
into the mix. And then Travis
goes and does all the work from
there, too. It's out into the
wild. And I don't see anything.
That's an absolute joy for at
least two thirds of the team.
Yeah, I mean, exactly.
Kevin: You guys remember, like
two months ago, when you were
like, We're going all in on
video Buzzcast. I was like,
that's, I mean, I will agree and
commit and disagree, disagree
and commit, I'll do something.
But I don't want to do this.
Alban: I never said that. The
only reason we ever did video
was because of you.
Kevin: That is true. I will take
that. Because when we first got
locked down, and we weren't
allowed to see anybody in
person, I was like, well, it
would be nice to be able to see
you guys when we record. And if
we're going to be doing video
chats Anyway, why don't we go
ahead and publish those. So I do
take the full blame for moving
us to video in the first place.
But how's that working out for
us?
Alban: Not good. The first one
we did was like a year ago, we
did that live stream to our
YouTube channel. And that just
kind of grew into then we wanted
to play around with Riverside,
which was doing video remote
video recording, and then squad
cast launched video, remote
video recording. And I think,
you know, we've you kind of had
the tools, the tools were there.
So we started playing with the
tools and experimenting. And now
the experiment is coming to an
end, at least for now, at least
for now. So do we want to give
like the whole story of it, kind
of walk through why we made each
decision along the way? And
let's give the sparknotes what
we learned the highlights
sparknotes? Yeah, start at the
beginning. Kevin, why did you
want to start doing some video
Buzzcast.
Kevin: When we first started
recording Buzzcast, we would do
it together in the office in our
little studio space. And we
could play off of each other's
energy, right? I think, Listen,
I'll speak for myself, I'm not a
super high energy person. So it
helps for me to be sitting
across the table for somebody or
to see somebody else's reactions
to what I'm saying or when
they're speaking themselves to
be able to keep myself amped up
and engaged in the conversation
when we went audio only and
there was no video component, it
was hard for me to continue to
keep my energy high. And to stay
engaged. I've also got a little
bit of add that I'm I'm fighting
and dealing with at the same
time. So that part was was
necessary in order to be able to
just produce good content. What
I was interested in is that
since we're doing this video
component Anyway, why don't we
record this, we've always said
that YouTube is an interesting
opportunity for people to
promote their podcasts because
they do have the algorithm, they
do have the recommendation
engine. But you shouldn't just
publish your audio only there.
Because that doesn't feed into
the strengths of the algorithm.
So you're not even getting the
benefit. And you're taking all
this extra time to do that. In
fact, you could be you know,
putting yourself at a
disadvantage if you do that,
because then you get a bad
reputation with the algorithm.
So anyway, we were doing video,
why not go ahead. And while we
edit the podcast, the audio
version, why not edit the video
version and just stick it on
YouTube and see if we get a bump
from it. That is where you guys
come in on the analytical side
and say, Is this working is this
not I will say that the
constraints from just somebody
who's on the podcast are much
higher than I anticipated. It's
one thing when you're out of the
office, or if you're traveling
or you can't be here there to be
able to quickly grab a USB mic,
throw it in your bag go with
you. And you can record audio
from anywhere in the world, it's
not too hard to find a quiet
space, most hotel rooms are
pretty quiet. Or if you're
staying on Airbnb or something
that you can find a closet, you
can find a quiet space to record
audio, being able to travel with
a decent camera setup. Or if you
don't have a decent camera
setup, then you're using
whatever on your laptop, you're
constantly worried about your
background, like all this stuff
is going on. It's just a
different level of commitment
and what's required in terms of
being able to put a show out
every week or every other week.
So that has been added an extra
level of commitment to the show,
which again, not something that
we weren't willing to do, but
something that was a little bit
unexpected. Didn't know going
into it. And then from an
analytical side, like how
helpful was it actually, for us
growing the show? That's what
you guys have dug into. Right?
Alban: Yeah, I mean, we can talk
a bit about the analytics buzz
cast itself was getting more
attention, let's call it
attention than it ever had
before. We were getting between
the downloads that continued to
grow on the RSS side. And on the
YouTube channel being added to
that it was huge. And then we
started doing clips of Buzzcast
episodes. And those were doing
really well. And so if you
wanted to add all that up, it
was like wow, this show is
doubled in sighs This is great.
But we on the other side, were
kind of frustrated with the
growth of the YouTube channel.
We grew a ton the first year.
And we just kind of seen a lot
of slowing down of our growth.
We didn't know exactly why. And
we kept kind of digging into the
data. And I think it might have
been Jonathan first, or maybe it
was Travis, who said, I just
clicked through all of the last
videos. And I noticed most of
the Buzzcast ones lose
subscribers. And I was like,
That's not true. And then I
click through and went, Oh,
that's definitely true. I was
very skeptical by nature. And so
and then we started digging in
deeper. And I took, I think it
was like six different stats
that we use to kind of quantify
how valuable each individual
video is. And I just went back
and looked at, like the last 90
days, all the videos that were
created during that 90 day
period, I think we had 22
videos, or 26 videos, all of the
Buzzcast ones were in the worst
category, they were they
represented, like the very
bottom five episodes, or videos.
And, you know, we, I think
Travis, you had some good ideas
of why the Buzzcast ones were
performing near the bottom. But
in the end, we were kind of
doing the thing that we've
always criticized, we've always
criticized people who were
putting a static image on a
YouTube video on a YouTube
video, just having audio, you
know, we said that can crush an
existing valuable YouTube
channel. And we were crushing
our existing value bowl YouTube
channel, by adding this, you
know, some of this, basically
podcast content in video format.
Kevin: To clarify, we weren't
crushing it because we weren't
putting the static image when we
were putting real video up. But
we weren't playing in line with
the the rules of YouTube or to
use the algorithm in the
smartest and best way we were
confusing the algorithm. We were
publishing different lengths of
content, different formats of
content. And so we ended up is a
very important and valuable
channel for us for marketing our
software and telling the world
about what Buzzsprout can do for
you as a podcaster. We were
hurting that marketing channel
for us, right?
Alban: Yeah, I guess what I was
saying is, we were not being
hypocritical in the way that we
created the video, the content,
because we weren't publishing
the static image with the audio.
But the reason we say we
recommend everybody else not to
do that, is because what it's
doing is it's showing YouTube
that your content is low
quality, and it's a specific
type of content. It's audio plus
an image. Well, when we were
looking at it, YouTube was used
to a much higher production
quality, a very different type
of content for our channel. And
so I think people were
constantly confused. They're
running into videos that they
thought were going to be Travis
or Sarah jalon, doing an in
depth tutorial. And they were
clicking, and they were finding
me pontificating about Facebook
podcasts for 20 minutes. So
Travis, give us some more
insight, what's what are the
differentiators between our day
to day content are the bread and
butter that we do very well, and
what Buzzcast was doing on our
channel?
Travis: One thing to keep in
mind is when we create content
for Podcasting, Q&A, when we
create tutorials, things like
that, we have a very specific
aim for those videos. Right? So
we're trying to answer questions
really well, we're trying to
take all the knowledge and best
practices for how to be a
podcaster. And consolidating
that into a form factor. That is
something you could easily watch
in just a few minutes and get
all the information that you
need. And because we're able to
put that level of focus on it,
like Alan mentioned, the
production quality is better. We
have custom animations, and B
roll, which is just a fancy way
of saying we cut away to
different videos of models doing
things that match what we're
talking about on screen. And so
we're able to create a type of
content that works really well
in a YouTube ecosystem. And so
if your whole channel is that
kind of content, then YouTube
starts knowing Okay, if someone
we've kind of identified them as
a potential podcaster, and
they're asking a podcast related
question, Buzzsprout is going to
be the channel we recommend
because we know they have this
kind of content. The reason that
we split off Buzzcast the full
episodes into a separate channel
a couple of months ago, is
because we noticed that those
videos were not performing at
all at the same level as the
Podcasting, Q&A and other
tutorial videos were doing. And
that was a common practice we'd
seen with other youtubers That
created video podcasts, they
would create new channels for
them. And then if they had
clips, that would be a third
channel. So they would actually
have three channels, they'd have
their main YouTube channel, a
full podcast channel and a clips
channel, in order to make sure
that they were kind of playing
by the rules, the best practice
of YouTube. So these were all
things that we, you know, as we
were experimenting, we weren't
sure like, how far are we really
going to carry this book? Like,
how invested Are we going to get
into video Buzzcast. And so it
didn't make sense to spin up a
whole YouTube channel, we're
just going to do a couple
episodes and then retire it
right. So we tested in our on
our main channel first and said,
Okay, that's working. So then
what if we took the next step,
and we made it consistent? And
then what if we took the next
step and made a separate, and so
it's kind of like evolved over
time. And now to Kevin's point,
it's at the place where we just
wanted to make sure, if we keep
going on this trajectory, it's
going to serve you guys, it's
gonna make Buzzcast better for
you. And it's also going to make
sense in the grand scheme of the
other things that we're doing to
produce and create content. And
so we're now at this nexus point
where if we're going to be able
to go back and record in the
studio, you know, that has a
level of production that even
exceeds what we're currently
what we were doing before. And,
and so at this point in time, it
makes more sense for us to pause
it, knowing we can always turn
it back on later. But just to
double down and refocus our
efforts on the audio only
version of Buzzcast.
Alban: So if I can kind of tie
this together with what are the
best practices we have learned
for YouTube, and podcasting, in
particular, because podcasting
is really growing on YouTube,
one out of five people now who
say they listened to podcasts,
they listened to most of their
podcasts on YouTube, one out of
five, that's pretty remarkably
high numbers. That comes from
Edison research. I actually
interviewed Tom Webster this
morning, and he told me that so
it's definitely working there.
But it takes a lot to make it
work. And it was not stuff that
was going to make sense for us
to do. So. I think to do
podcasts, well on YouTube, you
probably need to be recording a
person so that you have that
live engaging element. Because I
don't know how to say this
exactly. But like, the level of
engagement you want to see
between the hosts during a audio
and a video medium is very
different. Right now, like I can
see Kevin and Travis and like
Kevin looks kind of
disinterested. That doesn't
bother anybody who's just
listening to this because they
go, Oh, Kevin's probably
listening attentively. But you
know what? But if we're on
video, I'd be the first comment
we ever got on one of our
Buzzcast episodes was why does
albot look so mad. And I was
like, Oh, that's just my face
looks. That's just me. Like,
that's just me not smiling. And
so that works perfectly fine.
When you're recording long
distance recordings. When it's
on video, it starts to look a
little weird. And you can either
kind of over fake enthusiasm, or
you can get together in an audio
studio get together in a studio
in person. So like, get together
in person, I think is a very
high recommendation, they should
try to get that number, you
know, if at all possible, then
you've also got to have like
multiple shots to be able to
keep it interesting. So that's
probably a camera on each host.
Maybe an additional wide angle
camera, you can see that we've
experimented this in some of our
Podcasting Q&A videos is
rolling, I think three different
cameras now all at once, and
then we flipped between them.
For us to do the three of us in
the studio would require us
probably to be shooting like
four or five cameras at a time.
And then the, you know, that
really ramps up the amount of
video editing that we're doing.
Okay, so we're buying a bunch of
cameras. We're buying, we're
doing more in video editing.
We're getting us all together in
the studio in the most
dangerous, dangerous COVID
hotspot United States right now.
So three negatives, and all for
the benefit of starting a new
YouTube channel that isn't
exactly in alignment with what
we want. So that's to kind of
wrap it up quickly. What how
we're thinking about this. Maybe
we come back, maybe not. But
until next time, listen to us on
our RSS backed podcast.
Travis: Yes, we are definitely
not going anywhere. You'll just
need to listen to us anywhere
except for Spotify will be.
Alban: This is basically Apple
podcasts and indie apps
exclusive now. Yeah, I would say
so. I would say so.
Kevin: Yeah. I think it's an
interesting point that you
talked about when you talk about
your interview with Tom Webster
and he's saying that one in five
podcasts are roughly 20% of
people listening the podcast in
YouTube, and I can't help it
think that that is it just don't
think that there's a stat that
we should just take without some
additional thought, right? Like
listening to a podcast and
YouTube is a different
experience than what a lot of us
who produce podcasts are in the
podcasting space probably think
about when we think about
podcasting, like the benefits in
the beauty of podcasting is it's
it's passive, it's something
that you can do not only on
demand, but at your convenience
while you're doing other things
while you're doing housework
while you're exercising, while
you're at work while you're
driving a car, you the YouTube
experience is different than
that. And so while the YouTube
ecosystem is huge, and it might
be a lot more mainstream in
terms of the number of people
who engage in that space, and
then at some point, click on
something that is calling itself
a podcast, it's, it might just
be an exposure thing, it might
just be the size of the
ecosystem thing, it might not
necessarily be what we would
consider a podcast and all the
great benefits that go along
with podcasting. And I don't
want to get into the details of
is it does it really have an RSS
feed and all that stuff, that's
not really what I'm talking
about. I'm just kind of talking
about the size of the medium and
the number of people who at some
point during their normal day,
flip open YouTube, and might
click on something that is
calling itself a podcast. So
that being said, YouTube is a
fine place for you to distribute
content and being creator. But
hopefully, there's some
takeaways from what we've
experienced over the past year,
pressing into the YouTube Space
a little bit in terms of putting
a podcast onto YouTube, there's
a lot more that goes into it
than just recording a zoom call,
and then throwing it up there.
If you really want to succeed,
you have to understand the
algorithm, you have to
understand how the medium works,
you have to understand what type
of content works there is, this
is a larger level of commitment.
And you might find a huge
audience and huge following
there. But it's probably not
going to be it's not an
overnight success. It is a lot
of work. And it is very
different than audio only
podcasting. So as we continue to
unpack, and learn things about
how to use YouTube, or other
channels to grow your main
podcast, your audio only
podcast, it's distributed
through RSS, we will continue to
share those learnings with you
and hopefully make you a better
podcaster. But this is where we
are today. And the decisions
we've made. So this podcast will
not be on YouTube, and not in
video form. And as we learn more
and grow more, we'll share all
our learnings with
Travis: so if you've been a
Buzzcast listener for any length
of time, you know, we're big
fans of the podcast index and
podcasting 2.0, that entire
group, that entire working group
of people dedicating themselves
to improving the open podcast
ecosystem, and creating really
fun new features that allow you
as a creator, to make awesome
content and help your listeners
really engage with your show in
some really unique ways. Kevin
and Tom had an opportunity to
sit down with Dave Jones, who is
working on the podcast index and
podcasting 2.0 to talk about a
new feature that Buzzsprout is
now supporting, and also tease
out some fun new things that
they have coming down the
pipeline. So here's that
conversation between Kevin Tom
and Dave Jones.
Tom: This is Tom Rossi,
technical co founder of
Buzzsprout. And I am glad to be
joined by Dave Jones, one of the
two guys running the podcast
index, Dave Jones and Adam curry
have been doing amazing work
with the podcast index. Dave,
welcome to the show. Thanks for
all that you're doing. Tell us a
little bit about the podcast
index and what you guys are
doing over there.
Dave: Let's see, what are we
doing at the podcast? And what
are we not doing at podcast?
Kevin: So Dave, the podcasting
to auto project is like it
incorporates the podcast index
and the podcasting namespace
right and a whole bunch of
things. Can you tell us like
what's the difference? What are
the two functions that those
those two things sort of where
they come together? How does it
all work?
Dave: Yeah, we get this question
a lot. What the heck are y'all
doing with all these various
projects? And then what did they
even mean? And so podcasting 2.0
is the name of our podcast, but
it's also the name of the
broader movement of trying to
preserve, protect and extend the
open RSS ecosystem,
Kevin: right. When we say this,
this is a little bit different
than what like fireside chat
introduced it podcast movement,
is podcasting to Dotto, right.
Yeah,
Dave: I gotta hope it is
completely different. Yeah, but
podcasting. 2.0 is just an open
source, volunteer movement of
people coming up with ideas and
launching projects to help
preserve the open RSS ecosystem
of podcasting, and podcasting
inside the app. So pod inside
podcasting 2.0. But that would
be the podcast namespace where
all these new features and tags
are coming from. Also within
podcasting, 2.0 would be
something like pod ping, which
allows hosts to rapidly notified
apps and aggregators of new
episodes, things like that.
That's all in the podcasting 2.0
side of things. The podcast
index is the thing that we
created at the very beginning in
order to facilitate all these
other things. So the podcast
index is the largest directory
of podcasts on the internet.
It's were like 4.1 million
podcasts right now feeds. We are
a directory and also an API for
podcast app. to hook in to get
their podcast data from,
basically, they just start
coding an app, they plug into us
and they get all their data in,
it saves them a world of hurt on
that side of things. So those,
the podcasts index is the APN
directory, but geisen 2.0 is all
the features and community
movement.
Kevin: Right, and then huge
opportunity with the index is
that we're not tied in or
reliant on Apple anymore. So
like over the past two or three
months, Apple's directory has
been having a ton of problems.
Not to mention even before that,
when it was working, well, it
would take you probably a
minimum of two or three days up
to a couple weeks to even get in
Apple podcast directory, then
when you publish a new episode,
it might be 24 hours or more
before that new episode gets
released in search showing up on
any of the apps that rely on
that directory. And the index
solves all that along with other
technologies that you're
developing as well like the pod
paying and everything else.
Right.
Dave: Yeah, we started this
whole project with with the
directory and the API with the
idea that we wanted to take
Apple Apple's directory away
from being the center of the
podcasting universe, which has
been for, you know, 15 years at
least. And the idea there was
that, you know, no, no knock on
Apple, I mean, they've been good
stewards of podcasting, it's
just that it doesn't make a lot
of sense for an open
specification, like podcasting,
an open system that anybody can
participate in, it does not make
a lot of sense for that. To be
controlled by a single humongous
entity like apple, I mean,
they're literally the biggest
company in the world. And so
it's sort of like you have this
weird spectrum where you got
podcasting, which is completely
open, I can hand write an RSS
feed today, and get into the
inbox and create a podcast. And
I can do it from my computer in
five minutes. But then you have
the directory where all the
podcasts are found, his career
is controlled by this huge
corporation. So it really just
didn't didn't make a lot of
sense, the goal there was create
a directory that is completely
open, anybody can join it,
anybody can add to it, anybody
can put their podcast into it in
15 seconds. And then the next
step, which is the which is the
part that has to happen, make it
available for free, and
everybody can download it, you
can download it our entire
database right now from our From
the homepage of our website, and
do whatever you want with it,
you can go create your own
directory or your own API or
your own apps. So if it's not
free, then it doesn't solve any
of the problem. And if you have
to have us, it still doesn't
solve the problem. You need to
be we need to redistribute it.
And so that's what we that was
the Gulf in the beginning.
Tom: One of the features that
I'm most excited about out of
podcasting 2.0 is pod ping, can
you tell us a little bit about
that?
Dave: Yeah, sure. podcasting
suffers from the same thing that
all RSS based infrastructure
does it, what you have is a
system where you publish an
episode of whatever this is, or
a blog post or anything, any bit
of information, you publish that
to an RSS feed, think of it like
a WordPress blog. So then the
RSS feed, which is just a file
on a web server somewhere, it
gets updated. How does the rest
of the world know that you've
just put a blog post up on your
website, they have to be
notified, or they have to go and
check in there's, there's the
only two ways to get that
information. So just think of it
like, you know, clicking on a
website refresh button over and
over and over just to see if
something new pops up. That's
essentially what all of these
infrastructures have to do,
whether it's podcasting or
blogosphere, or any of these
things. It's just what you
resort to is just checking the
website over and over and over.
Tom: And this is this is one of
the things that we see all the
time, right, where we have
podcasters, who will publish an
episode. And then they're
wondering, Well, where is it? I
published it an hour ago? Why
don't I see it anywhere? Why
don't I see it on Apple? Why
don't I see it on Spotify? And I
think what what's exciting about
pod pain is this is a solution
to that problem, which is if you
subscribe to a feed with with
pod pain, you'll know whenever
it gets updated. You'll know
about it immediately.
Dave: Yeah, and that's a just a
reversal of that whole thing of
instead of checking over and
over and over for new content.
We tell you, you know, the
publisher tells you when there's
content,
Tom: pod ping solves two
problems. One is the polling
with RSS feeds. And then you
also have the problem of much of
the web sub pub pub is built on
Google, which isn't reliable. So
pod ping does it in a reliable
way. And so as I've talked to
people about pod paying, and
they said, Well, don't we
already have a solution for
this? Well, we don't have a
reliable solution for this. And
so that's why a lot of people
just continue to pull RSS feeds.
So really excited about the work
that you did with with pod Ping.
One of the features of the
podcast namespace that we've
just implemented at Buzzsprout.
That I'm sure everyone would
love to hear why we did it. Is
the gu ID, or the gu ID. How do
you say Dave gwit? Yeah, let's
Duguid. Goo it sounds gross.
Let's do good. There's no way
around it that it's He's gonna
sound gross. So but tell us
what, what's the grid? And why
do you want podcasting companies
like Buzzsprout and podcasters.
to include this in their RSS
feed,
Dave: a grid is a globally
unique identifier, geo ID. It is
a long number that uniquely
identifies a thing and object
globally in the world. It's this
thing is this number. And so
that is a thing that Apple's
directory has always had.
Everybody's podcast has an
iTunes ID, or an apple podcast
ID. And if you go and look for
your podcast on Apple's podcast
directory, you can see at the
end of the little URL in the
address bar up there, you can
see your Apple ID, because Apple
has been the center of the
podcasting universe for so long,
that iTunes ID has become the
way that many apps identify a
podcast in there's problems with
that. We solve those problems
earlier this year, when Apple's
API stopped returning the
location of where podcast live
at. So they stopped returning in
their API for many, many feeds,
they stopped returning the
actual URL, which is would be
like, you know, buzzsprout.com
slash such and such. That's a
huge problem because it broke
tons of apps. And we were on the
front lines of that, because a
lot of people started using our
API when that happened, because
it broke and broke their app.
Kevin: Is this stuff going to
help us move in the direction of
like global comments, global
ratings and reviews? Are you
guys working on infrastructure
to be able to allow podcasters
to leave a five star rating in
one app that then translates
over to another app or a comment
over here on pod friend that
could get posted in pod chaser?
Dave: Yeah, I hope so. I mean,
that's the idea. That's, that's
absolutely the goal with this.
Tom: Just a quick note for our
Buzzsprout listeners, don't you
don't have to write into the
port and ask us to put a grid on
your RSS feed, they're already
there. So all these features
whenever we can we want to
implement them without having to
require, you know, any, any kind
of, you know, technical
knowledge on our podcasters. And
so, yes, the goods are already
there. And we continue to follow
all the work that Dave and Adam
are doing, and we will implement
those features as they come up.
Dave, thank you for being on the
show. Thank you for all the work
that you're doing to help make
podcasting. Awesome. We
appreciate it. And thanks for
being here.
Kevin: Yeah, thanks, guys.
Appreciate it. listeners, please
check out podcast index.org
click on apps, download a new
podcast app, recommend it to
your listening audience. And
yeah, support the movement. It's
really good stuff for podcasting.
Travis: So we asked the good
people of the internet, namely
on our YouTube community chats
if you subscribe to the YouTube,
the main Buzzsprout YouTube
channel, you may have seen this
in your subscriber feed. Alban
asked on Twitter, we also posted
in the Facebook group, the
Buzzsprout podcast, Facebook
group, just your questions. So
we're going to run through a
lightning round, have a bunch of
questions and hopefully will
give you some okay answers.
Alright, so the first question,
Alban, I want to see this off to
you first, because you're going
to be the best person to answer
this question. This is from
Arielle, she asks, Why is Alban
the coolest? No,
Alban: no, no. Why is Alban the
coolest? My response to that
because that was to my asking
people questions was please
delete this. So yeah, no answer
to that. plead the fifth. Hmm.
Next question.
Travis: Kevin, do you have a
rebuttal response?
Kevin: I agree. It's puzzling.
He is the coolest. Nobody really
can explain why but she's right.
Ariel, one of our good friends.
Just start a podcast movement
works with squad cast. Awesome
software. Awesome People. So
check them out. Thanks for the
question. Ariel. Sorry, we don't
have a better answer for you.
Travis: He just is. It's just
the sky is blue. Alban is cool.
And podcasts are awesome. Next
question comes from Julio. And
Julio wants to know about
automatic social promotion. Is
there an automatic way to post
to social media accounts
automatically from your RSS
feed? Okay,
Alban: so yes, there is a way to
do it. I think the way that I've
seen most people do it is
through Zapier or Zapier,
depending on how you want to
pronounce that name, it's, you
know, you pretty much have it,
check the podcast feed once an
hour or something if there's new
episode, then kick off these
tweets and these social posts.
So there's a way to do it. I
would advise Julio not to do it,
though. This is one of the
marketing things that like
everybody really wants an
automated solution for we're
like, wouldn't it be cool if I
didn't have to write all my
tweets, instead, I just did the
thing I'm already doing and then
some software. Sometimes people
say AI, even if it's not AI,
that some thing will go and do
all the work for me. And that
would be cool. It'd be very
cool. What It ends up happening
is, you end up tweeting the
exact same tweet, once a week,
or four times a week with just
different links. And the only
people I know who I've seen do
this, it's like, those don't get
any engagement. No one's liking
them. Because the algorithm can
see and like your followers can
see, like, just a link to some
random website plus your
boilerplate text. Much, much
better would be for you, if you
think there's a quotable element
of your podcast to go create a
audio gram or a soundbite and
share that. If you're
overwhelmed by all the
promotion, like I've got five
different social channels and
only one person to do all the
work. Well, then the right
answer, I think, is pick one
social channel and write one
tweet, one Instagram post one
story, whatever it may be, for
each episode, and get that out
there. And you will I think, do
better just by doing one manual
action than trying to set up
this automated solution that
will pretty quickly fade into
the background noise of Twitter
and the rest of the social
platform. So my recommendation
is probably don't do it.
Kevin: Alright, good advice. And
if you decide not to take
Alban's advice that SAP yours
EAP i e r dot get answered. Next
question came in from we don't
know who anonymous question is,
should we auto distribute to
YouTube? timely question, we
Travis: just this is a similar
question. So I would say, go
back to the first part of this
episode, where we talked about
why we're pausing video
Buzzcast. It is the rare
exception. Where a podcast can
auto publish a video of a still
image with an audio file playing
in the background and have any
level of success and we're
talking, I can count on like one
hand, the number of podcasts
that I know, do this, and they
have they do you get some
traction. I'm thinking Tim
Ferriss, I'm thinking of all but
like not very many beyond that.
And that's simply because it's
not what YouTube is built for
people don't go to YouTube to
not watch something, they go to
YouTube to watch videos. So any
kind of automated YouTube
distribution is going to strip
the video element out. And that
kind of defeats the purpose of
putting it on YouTube,
Alban: start with the video, and
then take the audio to put on
your podcast. The other way
around is not as valuable. Sorry
to interrupt your question traps.
Travis: No, that was a perfectly
fine way to sum it up.
Kevin: Good advice. Next
question came in from Rick, how
long should your podcast title
be?
Travis: Here's the good news.
There are no rules that I'm
aware of other than, you know,
there's a certain maximum number
of characters Kevin, do you know
off the top of your head? What
the max number of characters is
for?
Kevin: It's got to be it's got
to be big?
Alban: It's something like 255,
right? Yeah,
Travis: it's quite long. So if
it fits in a tweet, you can make
it an episode title. So the
strategy becomes how do you
create an episode title that
gets your listeners to say, I am
going to listen to another
episode this week. Or if you're
using some kind of podcast SEO
strategy, where you're trying to
get those episodes to show up
inside of podcast apps, then
you'd want to make sure that the
title captured those those
keywords. There's no rhyme or
reason to how long the title
should be. There are some
podcasts that have quite long
titles, again, thinking about
the Tim Ferriss show where he
has like the whole summary of
the episode in the title. And
depending on the app that
someone's listening to it in,
you'll see more or less of it.
And then you'll see the little
ellipses at the end, if it's
runs over the kind of like a lot
of space there. But in general,
just hit the high point, what's
the main thing people can expect
to get out of the episode, make
it really clear up front, and
however long it needs to be is
how long it needs to be.
Kevin: Yeah, and I'll throw in
my little tip because I listened
so much in the car. And I use
Apple CarPlay to do that. And
whatever app you're using
everything in the Apple CarPlay
interfaces is blown up huge. And
so you really don't see very
many characters at all. So I
would say regardless of how long
your episode titles are, I don't
know that that's super
important. But please put the
most important information at
the front like we'll use the Tim
Ferriss example, because you
already brought it up. But like
I already know it's Tim Ferriss
show, so don't say Tim Ferriss
show podcast episode number yet,
like that's gonna be the same
for every single episode put,
like the guest name first, like
Tell me who's on there. So
regardless of the app that I'm
using, or how much they decide
to show, I'm seeing the relevant
information at the beginning,
not the same thing over and over
for every episode. Indeed,
Travis: wise words. Kevin, I
want to queue this one up to you
as our technical expert here.
This is from dog tail storytime,
podcast can turntables free
features help you grow your
audience because there is a free
chargeable and then you can pay
for some other stuff,
Kevin: right? So here's what I
would say about charitable I'm
not exactly up to date on what
they give you in their free plan
versus the different paid tiers.
And one of the reasons that I'm
not is because of the way that
charitable, like implements
their technology, they to use
most of the powerful features of
charitable you, they're gonna
want you to put in a URL prefix
on your RSS feed. So that's
something that you can totally
do as a Buzzsprout podcaster, we
don't limit you or not let you
do that, you can absolutely do
that. But what I'm not familiar
with enough, because we've just
never looked into doing it
ourselves is, we as soon as you
do that, you turn over all your
privacy, like all all the
information, your IP addresses
of all of your audience to
chargeable. And I know that they
do some attribution. So they
then have code that different
businesses can put on their
websites to look for overlapping
IP addresses between the people
who are downloading podcast
episodes and the people who are
landing on websites. And then
what they're doing on those
websites like, are they buying
certain products? Are they
checking out, they use some of
that technology to retarget
them. So if they show up, they
listen to this episode, and they
land on this website, they might
want to show them an ad for
something similar from another
podcast or something. All of
that stuff kind of goes against
things that I'm into things that
I get excited about. it rubs me
it rubs my privacy button the
wrong way. Like I don't love
tracking, I love. I love
targeting, like the idea that
saying, hey, this podcast is
intended for this type of
audience. So if you're a podcast
sponsor, then that's something
that you should look at, because
this is content that's geared
towards people who are into
motorcycles, and who are the
types of people that are into
motorcycles? Well, it's mostly
these types of people. But we
can't identify any individual
motorcycle owner and say that
they also have this level of
education or could be this
gender, or might be this level
of household income. Like
that's, that's where the line
crosses for me. And charitable
is kind of more into the other
stuff. And so I don't know a
whole lot about it. But I would
tell you that if you're
interested in exploring
charitable, please read their
terms of service, please make
sure that you're comfortable as
a podcaster, that as soon as you
start hooking up their, your,
their tools to your podcast,
you're going to expose some
level of your listeners, your
privacy to them, and I don't
know what they do with it. So
please do some research before
you get into that. Not saying
it's not the smart move for you.
But just educate yourself before
you do it.
Travis: Next question is from
Stephen. And he has some premium
content that it seems like he
already has on Patreon. And so
his question is about adding
that premium content to Spotify
and Apple podcasts. So in
addition to Patreon, should he
offer subscriptions directly on
Spotify, or Apple?
Alban: So the answer to Stephen
will be a little different than
for everybody else. Steven is
actually the podcast host and
producer, Apple Insider. So he
does a lot of pretty produced
podcast episodes. It's very
tempting to say, Oh, of course,
do it. Why not put your podcast
episode everywhere? Because
that's what I would want to do
is make it easy for people who
are on Spotify to subscribe,
make it easy for people on Apple
to subscribe, make it easy for
anybody, anywhere else to
subscribe via Patreon. Why not?
Well, the why not is the amount
of work that that could take. So
there's quite a few. There's
just an article I read about I
believe was NPR was NPR hiring
two different people. And their
primary responsibilities was
uploading all of the podcasting
content to all these different
platforms. And double checking
to make sure they did the ads
free version there. This one got
that bonus content. This one, we
gave it the right title, blah,
blah, blah, being put everywhere
on the web, if you're an indie
podcaster. And you're just
saying, hey, I want to
experiment and see if I can make
a little money. Well, man, this
is really not a exciting
proposition, to add multiple
hours to your workflow to make
sure that your podcast episode
is put up all over the place.
But if you are a larger team,
and you have the resources of
something like Apple insider
behind you, like Stephen does,
that may well be worth the, you
know, the time and effort to
make sure it's as easy as
possible. The only slight
caveat, I guess I'd give it the
end is for Steve in particular,
the podcast is Apple and cider
is for people who are really
into Apple products. If they're
really into Apple products,
they're probably using Apple
podcasts or one of the other
dominant iOS apps. I just be
surprised if they got a huge
following over on Spotify as
paid platforms. But it'd be
interesting to see that but
yeah, so that's maybe how I
would think about that question.
Yeah,
Kevin: let me jump in here
quick. This is a bit of a
tangent off of the paid
subscription workflow in the
amount of work that you put into
it. Something to keep in mind,
you might hear oftentimes,
people say, make sure you have a
large enough following before
you start going into premium
content. And the reason that
like we've given that
recommendation and other people
As well as because it's the same
amount of work whether you end
up with one subscriber or 10,000
subscribers Exactly. And so
you're making a commitment to
the people who decide to give
you money for your premium
content that you're going to do
as extra work every week, you're
going to do the bonus episodes,
you're going to do the ad free
version, whatever it is that
you're promising, you're going
to do that whether one person
decides to pay you $5 a month,
or 50,000 do. And so make what
we say make sure you have a
large enough following before
you take this commitment. It's
because when we when you launch,
we want you to have enough
income coming in from your
premium offerings to justify the
effort that goes into it. And it
can be a large amount of effort.
So just think that through
before you jump into any
subscription or premium offering,
Travis: the next question comes
from Al Pete's, hey, longtime
listener, first time caller, how
important friend, how important
is it to have a team behind you
with your podcast?
Alban: Okay, well, to quote
Marilyn Monroe, maybe I'll save
this for later. I'm not I'm not
lucky locked in on you've got to
have a team. I mean, the Marilyn
Monroe quote, it's better to be
unhappy, alone and unhappy with
someone else. So I think this is
the way I've approached it.
Maybe I'm in a dark place of my
life.
Kevin: But there's another quote
that says misery loves company,
like those conflict.
Alban: Yeah, misery loves
company means like, if other
people are miserable, then
they're going to want to like
make you miserable, too, right.
And Marilyn, and rose saying,
like, I'm already having a rough
go of it. I don't need another
person who's having a rough go
of it. Also kind of venting
their stuff on to me, too.
Kevin: You think they're
complimentary. Okay,
Alban: I use if you're on a good
team, and it is a joy to work
with other people. It really is
like, it is so stinking nice to
like, show up and record this
show. And Travis has already put
together an outline, Kevin's got
suggestions, I throw my thoughts
into the mix. And then Travis
goes and does all the work from
there to it's out into the wild.
And I don't see anything. That's
an absolute joy for at least two
thirds of the team. Yeah, I
mean, exactly. But if you're on
a team, where let's say you're
the one making the outline, and
you're the one kind of carrying
the conversation, and you're
splitting the money three ways,
you know, let's say you're
actually making some money off
the show, it can get old, and it
can get really old, if like,
people are also changing the
recording time, or they're
supposed to create the social
media posts, but they don't. But
you're still editing the post
editing it. And we really
appreciate Travis, but I think
there's a lot of editors and
podcast producers, who don't get
a lot of credit for the amount
of work and thought that goes in
to that part of the show. The
the face, the voice of the show,
often is the one getting all the
credit. And so I would boil that
all down to sometimes it's
really great to be on a team,
sometimes it can be tough. And I
am constantly impressed by very
small teams that what they're
able to get done. The You know,
my first job ever was working
for the government, when I was
17, working in a library. And
like you just saw how slow
everything moved. And now
working on a really, really
small team that builds
Buzzsprout. It's a lot of fun to
see how quickly we can get
things done. So I think in some
future life where I'm a, you
know, I think anything, I would
not want to be on a smaller
team, not a bigger team. And
there's people in the podcasting
space who have teams of two or
three. And I bet that they're
loving it that way. So certain
things can only happen if you're
really big. But if you're small,
I think it's a good thing to
enjoy it and maybe don't grow
unless there really is a good
reason to do so.
Kevin: Yeah, let me tackle the
same question from a different
angle. Because you could also
look at it as like, what do you
have more of time or money if
you love doing your podcast, and
it's successful for you. And
whether you're doing it alone or
interviewing somebody
necessarily great, but you don't
have all the time to put into
the promotion, or you're not
giving it as much love as Mark,
you're not giving as much
marketing love as you would like
to or you don't have time to
edit it to the level of quality
that you want to then those are
things that money might be able
to solve for you. So you might
be able to maybe team isn't the
best word maybe it's it's think
about it in terms of help, like,
how important is it to have
help? Well, if you have
resources on the money side
moreso than on the time side,
then I think that's fantastic.
Well, a lot of us have more time
than money. And so in which case
you can learn to do this stuff
yourself. And there's great
resources on YouTube and
everything else. So I think just
kind of figure out where you are
and what works for you. I
wouldn't be afraid of using a
team. But I wouldn't necessarily
say you have to use a team
either. So whatever works for
you, so thanks for the question.
All right, next question came
from DJ s cube. DJ s KOB.
Alban: What ej S wave? DJ skewb
dj skewb Okay,
Kevin: what's the best way to
rebrand and retain your audience.
Travis: Oh, well, this one,
lucky for you, DJ Scoob is
relatively easy. We actually
have a video on our YouTube
channel that I'll link in the
show notes, where we talk about
rebranding, what used to be five
minute Mondays to what is now
Podcasting, Q&A. The biggest
things you want to think through
is make sure that your audience
knows what's happening before it
happens. So it doesn't happen by
surprise. They're not looking
for, you know, five minute
Mondays in their podcast
library, and they go and it's
not there, and they don't know
where it is or why it's missing.
And they didn't scroll down to
see Oh, there's this new podcast
called Podcasting Q&A, that I'm
happy to be subscribed to make
sure they know what's happening
ahead of time. And then when you
actually do the rebrand, make
sure that you're still serving
the same kind of person. So if
you start off as like a Star
Wars fan podcast, and then you
want to jump into home
gardening, it doesn't make sense
to rebrand that because it's
built to serve a different kind
of person, someone who's looking
for something different. And so
if you're rebranding it, like
changing the name to be, you
know, more dialed in or you want
to take your name out of it and
change something like, that's
totally fine. Just make sure
you're serving the same kind of
person. Otherwise, you're gonna
have better success, just
creating a new podcast from
scratch. Alban, we talked about
Facebook podcasts a couple times
here on the show, and we have
lots of thoughts on it. History
breeze podcast wants to know, is
there any update on Facebook
podcasts?
Alban: Do you actually know who
history briefs is?
Travis: I do not.
Alban: That's a our friend Brad
shrieve wonderful Ostuni show.
So if you want to hear short
stories about history, check it
out. Okay, so what's happening
with Facebook podcasts? Well, I
still am very bullish on it. I
think Facebook could open the
door to millions of new
listeners, if they ever decide
to really launch Facebook
podcasts, they announced a ton
very quickly. And then they had
a date to their was launching.
And it was only going out to
like 1% of podcasts, and only 1%
of Facebook iOS users in the
United States. So we're talking
like a super, super limited
quantity of people we're seeing
it. And it really hasn't
launched much more than that.
The only update I have is, you
know, we had one of our shows
how to start a podcast in there.
And that was cool. And I we
played around with a little bit.
And then I saw Buzzcast got
added. And that was cool. But I
went back in recently, because I
got an email that said your
podcast has been added to your
Facebook page. And I went in and
there are like 80 podcasts
associated with the Buzzsprout
Facebook page. Okay, well, why
is that because some of you know
Buzzsprout hosts over 100,000
active podcasts. And a bunch of
you are doing great shows that
Facebook has found and said, Ah,
these would be great on Facebook
podcasts, we are going to
automatically connect it to
their Facebook page. And they
have incorrectly identified that
Buzzsprout is the owner of that
podcast. And I have to imagine
the same thing is happening over
for all the other podcast hosts.
We didn't publish any of those
shows, obviously, because those
aren't ours to publish. And, you
know, if it was associated the
Buzzsprout page, it wouldn't
help you grow your podcast on
Facebook anyway. So I guess I'm
just saying, I still think this
could be good. I'm looking
forward to learning more,
they've got to get a nice way to
submit shows via RSS, or to at
least manually Connect shows
that they find to Facebook
pages. Because this totally
automated solution is definitely
not working now. But we saw
growing pains. In the beginning
of Spotify, we saw Growing Pains
like this, the beginning of
Amazon, to a much lesser extent.
And some even with beginning of
Google podcasts. It's reasonable
that we have them. Now with
Facebook. I'm sure it'll get
cleared out. But once this
launches, and once it there's an
easy solution. Brad, you'll be
one of the first people that to
know, because I think it could
be really big in the grand
scheme of things for podcasts.
It's gonna be huge, huge.
Facebook was very big for our
former president. So
Kevin: that's the next big thing
is when was that platform that
got canceled?
Alban: parlor?
Kevin: parlor podcasts coming?
Alban: We had them for a hot
minute. Do you not work? Okay,
so there are two parlour apps.
Kevin: There was doesn't have
enough editing work to do
already. Now we're gonna go into
the parlor.
Alban: This is a segment This is
the second podcast. All right,
Kevin: let me fire off another
question for you. What is the
least complicated platform for
recording? I'm assuming we're
talking about recording multiple
people remote, so let's steer it
in that direction.
Travis: All right, multiple
people remotes and we're gonna
set up a basic bar of a Audio
needs to be at least average,
right? There's lots of solutions
for, you know, capturing phone
calls and things like that, but
not really the level of quality
you'd want in a podcast, if you
just want super simple and very
intuitive zoom, surprisingly,
can give you some good audio if
you have all the settings tuned
correctly. So you'll want to
record separate audio files for
each participant, you'll want to
turn original audio on. So that
zoom isn't compressing the audio
file as it's being streamed back
and forth. And you'll want to
save it both locally to your
computer and to the cloud. At
the same time, if you have all
those settings turned on, and
the other person has the zoom
app download to the computer,
it's pretty intuitive. But if
you want something that is going
to give you that extra level of
quality, and the software that
we've used for Buzzcast that we
recommend for podcasting is
Riverside, and squad cast, both
of those will give you
completely lossless audio. So
whatever the microphone is
recording, that's what you're
going to get. And it's built
right into a web app. So you're
going to send someone a link,
they click it, and you can start
recording your podcast.
Fantastic. Alright, one more.
Kevin: Let's do one more. And
this is a tricky one. Luckily,
we have an expert on the panel
today. Can you use small
snippets of movie audio? Or
waves when discussing a film or
a show?
Alban: Can you?
Travis: Alban, you're the
expert. You tell us?
Alban: All right. Yeah, I guess
Kevin wants me to give my non
real this is like a fake thing.
But I am a lawyer. I'm not your
lawyer. I wasn't even a good
lawyer, even when I was a
lawyer. So I take all that into
account.
Kevin: Why Why do people do
that? album? sidebar? legal
term? Why? Why every time a
lawyer gives an answer on a
podcast or or TV show or
somebody that why do they say
that? What do they say I am a
lawyer, but I'm not your lawyer.
Why is that?
Alban: Okay? So there's actually
a lot of law around whether or
not a client or attorney client
relationship is formed. And so
sometimes people will like show
up in your office and be like,
blah, blah, blah, talk to you
about their case, and then be
like, cool, you're my lawyer.
And then you're like, No, no,
you're not my No, no, I'm not
your lawyer yet. And they're
like, Oh, yeah, you are. And you
can actually kind of get roped
into doing some legal work,
especially if you're already
like going to trial, even if
they're not paying your bills.
all that to say, you got to make
sure that people know when
there's a attorney client
relationship formed. And I think
that it's gone a little bit too
far when people are like, I'm a
lawyer, but not your lawyer,
like no one in their right mind
is thinking like this random
anime avatar lawyer on Twitter,
like re tweeting back at you is
actually their attorney. No one
thinks that there's a
relationship there.
Kevin: So just to be clear,
Alban, you are my attorney, but
you're not the listeners.
Attorney. Right? I actually.
Okay, so can I use a clip from a
movie or a TV show? Can I put it
in my podcast? And if I do that,
am I gonna get in trouble?
Alban: Alright, so the what
they're kind of hinting towards
is copyright law, and
specifically fair use. So if
something is copyrighted, you
can't use it in your podcast?
Well, you can, but then you will
get sued. And then people are
most people are savvy enough.
They're like, but sometimes I
know that stuff is in in things.
And there's this thing called
fair use. Yeah, there is there
is a legal defense to a
copyright suit called fair use.
And that's when you're using me
it would be like if your Do you
there's different ways you could
say we're using it for
educational purposes. I'm only
using this in a satirical way
I'm using it. In a way I think
that modifies the original I
forget the legal term for that.
It's been a long time since I
didn't do well on copyright law.
But all that to say, yeah, you
can use stuff, but then you get
sued for it. And then you try to
prove to the judge that it was
an acceptable fair use. That's
not the situation you want to
find yourself in for your movie
podcast. What is much better is
to just talk about the podcast,
or to actually get to license
whatever, you know, whatever
license you need to get to
actually share those clips. This
is definitely not the end.
Another thing to think about is
a lot of different platforms are
scanning to find content that
is, you know, violating
copyright, because of DMCA. So.
YouTube has bots that are
checking every video going, Hey,
is there any Miley Cyrus music
in here, and if it is like, turn
it off, turn off this video and
let Miley Cyrus give you a
strike on your account. So
that's going on in the
background for all a lot of
these channels. Spotify, YouTube
in particular, I'm sure Apple
has some as well, if you're on
any of those platforms, even if
you have the copyright, it can
get a little dicey because the
bot picks you up says, Oh,
that's copyrighted music, turn
it off. And then you've got to
actually work with that platform
to be like, no YouTube, I
actually have rights to this. I
mean, there's so many kind of
funny examples of people
uploading their own music to
YouTube, and YouTube goes, Oh,
this is copyrighted. And they're
like, yeah, by me, I gotta turn
this off for a bit. So all that
to say, don't, it's not worth
the hassle. I have heard of
people who do shows that involve
a lot of music, or movie
trailers or stuff that is
copyrighted on Patreon. And they
put all of it behind the
paywall, and my only thinking is
the only people who see it are
paying subscribers. And there is
no algorithm running around
checking for copyrighted
material that is a copyright
violation that is just unlikely
to be caught. So wouldn't
recommend it. But um, yeah,
don't use it. Be good. Don't do
bad things.
Kevin: Alright, challenged to
that answer. I listened to
podcasts like Seth Rogen does
the akimbo podcast, and people
do it on talk radio all the
time, they play these little
clips, like whatever, you know,
a little sound from the Seinfeld
show, or a famous one liner from
friends episode or something
like that, just as like little
transitions where they make a
joke, and they get, you know,
they're like, you know, for
whatever reason, new moon or
something like that, like comes
in, like, how do they get away
with that? And can I do
something like, to that extent
on my podcast without trouble,
Alban: I need to go pull it up,
Kev, I mean, you're, you're
still in your landing into Fair
Use space again. And so you
could still end up like, I think
all of those radio stations like
some, you know, whoever owns the
rights to Seinfeld. Now, Fox
could be like, Alright, let's go
after him for that. It's just a
big difference if like your
radio station, or you're a
pretty big company that actually
has a lawyer on staff that can
be like, Oh, I can respond to
the threatening letter. I can
respond to YouTube when they're
trying to get this taken down.
Versus I'm an individual. And
all of a sudden, I'm dealing
with this massive issue, at
least in your mind. I mean, you
get one cease and desist letter.
Most lawyers, like when we get
cease and desist letters are
like, yeah, these get sent out
all the time. And a lot of
times, there's no suit even
coming after, after them. But if
you're an individual, and you
get a cease and desist letter,
you're like, Oh, my gosh, I
can't go spend 10 grand and hire
an attorney. I can't fight this.
We're talking about a podcast
with 80 listeners. Well, as soon
as that happens, now, you're
going back in and re editing all
your episodes to take out these
segments, you're taking down
episodes. It just throws a huge
wrench into your life is like
did that ever improve the
podcast anyway? I don't think
so. So that's my take on why I
would probably leave it out.
Well, Albert, I
Travis: think that's fantastic.
Official lawyer Lee advice.
Kevin, are you gonna say?
Kevin: Well, every now and then
this does happen. And some of
our customers get cease and
desist letters and they get sued
and they say like, what can you
do to help me and we can only
have like one response, which
is, I know a lot of people want
to send water. Just send your
cash. Alright, wrap us up.
Travis: If you want us to do
more of these a lightning round
Question and Answer segments,
make sure that you tell Alban on
Twitter. that'll probably be the
fastest way to get to one of us
and let us know that you really
liked that. We did this. That's
it for today. We'll get to the
next one. Keep podcasting