Adam Curry: podcasting 2.0 March
4 2023 Episode 124 on D flat
formable hello everybody welcome
to a delayed board meeting of
podcasting 2.0 preserving,
protecting and extending the
open independent podcasting
ecosystem that's what we're all
about. And we talk about it once
a week with everybody in the
board meeting everything
happening at podcast index.org
Of course the podcast namespace
and everything at podcast index
dot social. I'm Adam curry here
in the heart of the tech show
country and Alabama. The man who
fills up your generator say
hello to my friend on the other
end. Ladies and gentlemen, Mr.
Dave Jones.
Unknown: Adam Clark curry. Yes.
Dave Jones: Don't for one day.
Party.
Adam Curry: Why are you being
stern with me? You threw out an
Adam Clark curry that triggered
me right away.
Dave Jones: Yeah, no, I knew it
would.
Adam Curry: David Ashley Jones.
Dave Jones: Yes. There's only
one I only have one rule and
then no part no part long gone.
Adam Curry: But we cleaned up.
There was only Dame DeLoreans
panties apparently around the
flagpole. Everything else was
clean. We didn't do anything.
Anything bad. I'm so sorry.
Dave Jones: It was much
entertaining.
Adam Curry: Oh, well. You heard
it while you're at the office
listening.
Dave Jones: I got a bootleg. I
got somebody sent me a bootleg.
Okay, I
Adam Curry: purposely did not
record because I didn't want any
evidence that we were breaking
the law not only breaking the
law by playing two and a half
hours of licensed music on the
stream, but also taking money
for it which which is, I think a
super violation.
Dave Jones: There there is there
is a bootleg if you know the
right guy down on Fifth Avenue,
behind the corner.
Adam Curry: Canal Street is what
you're talking about Canal
Street.
Dave Jones: With enough sets you
can get a you can get a bootleg
for those
Adam Curry: who are wondering
what we're talking about.
Yesterday, we were ready to go
for our regular regularly
scheduled board meeting time.
And well there were two things
that happen actually, I now the
hill country here in Texas had
had a pretty big storm. I have
Thursday, Friday and Thursday
and Thursday morning was really
bad with golf ball sized hail,
which sounded great against our
metal roof. In the morning, I
was crazy. I was I mean the dog
was freaked out. I have not seen
our dog freaked out by anything.
But this freaked her out. And
then Friday it just I mean, it
really missed Fredericksburg and
went right past us. Some prayer
was involved, I'm sure. But
Dave Jones: yes, diversionary
prayer. Yes, I forgot.
Adam Curry: Yes, but I forgot to
add a diversionary tactic for
you. And it hit pretty hard. So
So now, somewhere down the line,
my bandwidth was totally
crapping out my upstream was
about 500 kilobits per second,
which is not the typical
upstream. And that just as as I
was figuring that out, you know,
bringing out different access
points. I've gotten, you know,
I've got T Mobile Verizon, I
have, if all else fails, I've
got Starlink, although that does
introduce some latency. So we're
messing around with that. And
then Dave goes, Oh, bad signal.
The power went down in the
office. What happened there?
Dave Jones: Yeah, yeah, that's
so yeah, I guess yesterday was a
total cluster. I mean, like, I
got in the car, even going back
before what? What happened with
the show, I got in the car, to
leave to go to the office for
work. And I get a ping on my
phone. I look down at the phone
and it says, you've got a guest,
Mike, Michael and Sam from wave
lake at 9am. Oh, right. What?
None, right? No. 30. And so I
get to the office and I emailed
them. And I'm like,
Adam Curry: and they're always
there. We're sitting ready. They
got the headphones on everything
good.
Dave Jones: I was like, Hey,
guys, please tell me this was a
this was a timezone mix up. And
I didn't actually send you a
load report. And they were like,
No, you send it for nine. I was
like, damn it.
Adam Curry: How does it? How
does that happen? Because you
use you know, use Google use
your calendar for that.
Dave Jones: Now use fast mails,
calendar, but it's all through
the iPhone. I don't think I've
ever messed that up in in a
mess. I just totally boned it. I
mean, like, it was terrible. And
then it turned out it was it was
actually good that they didn't,
they didn't that we had to move
the interview because then all
that stuff happened with your
bandwidth and then the power
went off at work. And so then I
was like, I gotta go back. I
mean, I gotta get back to the
office now.
Adam Curry: Does it blip or does
it fail over nicely to the to
the UPS is that handle the
switch over to the generator?
Dave Jones: Yes, it's same. It's
seamless. But see, we have for
four reasons. We can't get
natural gas. We have diesel
generator. And so
Adam Curry: you are single
handedly responsible for climate
change right now.
Dave Jones: If I was and I was I
was pouring five gallons of
climate change into the
generator with every jug less
than
Adam Curry: five gallons of
climate change coming right up.
That's how they should measure
it. Oh my god, yeah, pretty
climate change.
Dave Jones: And that's the so I
got like, the lightning struck
the power pole that feeds our
building and we have three phase
power. So it took one of the
lines, it was just gone. I mean,
like it just blew the thing off
the pole. And
Adam Curry: what the whole
transformer blew right off the
pole.
Dave Jones: There wasn't a
transformer it's like it's like
there's it's three phase so you
get three lines coming in in one
one of the connector lines that
go off the main was just gone.
And so the power of come they
came out
Adam Curry: you didn't get your
your your gear out and clamp in
the pole and reconnect that
thing.
Dave Jones: I don't I don't
know. I don't do a lot of poll
work these days.
Adam Curry: These days.
Dave Jones: Now now I'm on all
this. Now, because the isobar is
working so well now I'm just
feet. I'm trying to feed the
isobar as much as I can I sell
Adam Curry: bought is
unbelievable. I love I was just
telling Tina, how that works is
that how does that happen? How
do they even do that? It's magic
map. They have running, running
some kind of transcript in real
time.
Dave Jones: But I got home about
one o'clock in the morning.
Adam Curry: Oh my goodness.
Power was back on by them.
Dave Jones: Yeah, where they
fixed so we had to turn because
it wasn't actually all the way
out. It was just it was out of
phase. Only one of the lines was
gone. So things were like
flickering lights. were flashing
like disco tech. Yeah.
Adam Curry: Phasing. Oh, that's
fantastic.
Dave Jones: That was horrible.
It was scary. So they were like
yeah, we're shutting the whole
thing. We're just shutting the
whole Yeah, make sense. Anyway,
so did didn't want that. But it
was it was just a weird, man.
It's just a weird weekend so
far. Very strange.
Adam Curry: Well, I'm so hot
man. So and you and your work
today as well at the office? I
did. Yeah. Because he went right
back in at nine o'clock. No. Was
there eight? Yeah. After getting
home at one.
Dave Jones: Yeah, but I'm gonna
I'm gonna sleep really good
tomorrow. Okay, I'm making that
today. I'm making up for it.
Tonight. I took a shower, before
the show to like, wake myself up
getting myself fired up.
Adam Curry: Yeah. You're lit.
Dave Jones: Lit and lit. is lit
as I can
Adam Curry: get this show is
lit, which is the formula for
for success. As far as I'm
concerned. This is a live item
tag where if you use the
appropriate podcast app, you'll
actually get an alert for this
pod verse seems to be the one
that's doing it the best I think
podcast addict has it and don't
is that out of beta yet. The
podcast addict alert system.
Okay. And of course, Europe
curio caster. I was looking at
the charts yesterday. With me
spinning our tunes for two and a
half hours, something really
magically happened. And to me,
it was yeah, it happens during a
regular show, too. But there's
something about the audience
participation that just went
with the flow. And, you know,
because of course we have the
chat room when you when you use
pod verse, the chat room opens
up, you get the live signal. You
go into the live the live item
right there and your list. You
can chat along and you can boost
in real time. And I think was
Todd Cochran. Mr. Blueberry, he
started off. He's like 25,000
SATs and he wanted a song. And
he said right there, the next
request has to be five more. And
it was like, Okay, the next one
was 30,000. And then I think,
was Carolyn Blaney. She sent
20,000 requested something, but
blueberry came in and said, I'm
gonna add 15,000 to make up so
it's 35 for her request. And
people just do things up and up
and up, like 5060 70,000 SATs
and requests and I'm like, stop.
First of all, I was embarrassed.
Yeah. But also, I discovered
something else. When you open up
the stream to requests, you get
a lot of shit. It's not really
necessarily in the groove of the
dance party. Metallica Okay,
right? Yeah, I like Metallica
too. It's just, you know, and
then followed by polka music
from Weird Al Yankovic it was it
was a little a little hectic, it
was all over the spectrum. But
we had a good very reminiscent
Dave Jones: of FUBAR Fridays
with the Dropbox.
Adam Curry: Daily source code.
Exactly.
Dave Jones: Yeah, that was all
over the map to like some of the
some of those was like, okay,
yeah,
Adam Curry: yeah, yeah. But it
was it was really fun. And it
was just nice to see everyone
kind of go with the flow. And
that's something that we're
bringing something really
beautiful back that existed
many, many many years ago. I
mean, these days you even have
Okay, I should probably play
this chat GPT is now doing radio
GPT they're literally pitching
AI voices to run your radio
station. And I got to play this
this little demo they have. So
as I've done a lot of top 40
radio work certainly in the in
the 90s, late 80s, early 90s it
already was very formulaic. Now
you had a lot of leeway
depending on who you were what
time slot you have, you know
what station, but in general,
Steve Kingston legendary program
director who was at GE 100 When
I was there, he would say, Hey,
man, and a monkey could do this.
Just read the liner cards and
hit the button. And literally,
that's it always ended with z
100.
Dave Jones: That's in New York,
right? Z. When
Adam Curry: do you want 100?
Toby? Yeah, I was brought in by
Scott Shannon, who's the legend
who I've you know, had probably
any of my radio career to thank
because I emulated him so much.
So the I all the elements that
you know, just for the regular
jocks I will say for you know,
except for drive time in the
morning, and drive time in the
afternoon. everyone kind of has
to follow these rules overnight.
You could break some some, some
rules and stuff, but now they
still the most expensive part of
any organization is going to be
people so screw the DJs get rid
of the button pushers. We don't
even need monkeys anymore.
Listen to this promo from radio
GPT. And by the way, everything
that they're talking about is
something that you are told and
trained to do as a disc jockey.
These days eatery
Unknown: is revolutionizing the
audio industry with the launch
of radio GPT, the world's first
AI driven localized radio
content solution. Ready radio
GPT combines the power of GPT
three technology with future
ease AI driven story discovery
and social content system Rubik
posts, as well as AI voice tech
to provide an unmatched
localized radio experience for
any market any format or grid
using q3. Link. Topical system,
along with AI voice technology,
radio GPT brings a radio station
to life.
Adam Curry: It brings the radio
station to life.
Dave Jones: It actually kills.
Unknown: I can see what's in
your music log and talk about
the songs or artists on your
station. Oh, wow,
Dave Jones: you're dead.
Unknown: I can see what's
happening in your local market
right now and talk about it in
real time. Right? It looks like
the Dairy Queen is flooded. I
can post on your Facebook,
Instagram, Twitter and tick tock
during my show. Hey, I'm
Adam Curry: doing a show. Listen
Unknown: to me talk about what's
coming up.
Adam Curry: I'm going to record.
Unknown: I am great at teasing
and pre promoting content going
into breaks.
Adam Curry: Oh, you're teasing.
Oh, yeah. Coming up next on 100.
Unknown: I can talk about the
weather or traffic is nice. I
can see how many people are
listening right now through
future streaming and say hello
to certain locations.
Dave Jones: Oh, Cleveland.
Unknown: I can take open mic
audio from listeners using
future immobile and incorporate
their thoughts. Oh, yeah, the
Rockies
Dave Jones: go Oh, yeah,
Adam Curry: that'll that'll end
well. I think gone are the days
of Shindig, what was your
favorite radio station?
Unknown: questions and feedback
into my show. I can share news
updates and current events
relevant to your audience's
interests and demographics.
Adam Curry: Okay, she knows my
interest in demographics. But
Donna had a buddy and plans.
Unknown: I have experienced
conducting engaging interviews
with notable guests and experts
now.
Adam Curry: This is the one this
is the one that I'm like you're
gonna do an interview with
notable guests okay?
Unknown: You can give away
prizes, tickets, and exclusive
experiences to listeners through
on air contests using future
mobile splash contesting
Adam Curry: flash contesting it
should be Whoa, would you be
contrasting but okay,
Unknown: I am skilled at
creating unique and entertaining
breaks that keep your audience
engaged and coming back for
more.
Adam Curry: So this this drivel
and by the way, they have a
video of this of this AI bot she
doesn't blink and trust me to be
a good podcast or like me you
got to blink have to read all
kinds of ticks otherwise you
just no good you got to have
that
Dave Jones: most that's the
bottom bar
Adam Curry: is not blinking. So
this of course is atrocious. But
this will this will get get
radio airtime people will do
this. And compared to what we
had going on yesterday. It's
there's just no comparison that
the thing lived it live. And
people were feeding back in real
time. The whole thing was just a
beautiful experience. It was so
special about it
Dave Jones: as a DJ Yeah. I
mean, so this is this was great.
So I'm listening to the bootleg.
And, and, and it's it reminded
me so you weren't expecting
thing. You weren't expecting for
things to go in that direction?
No, I was not like better No,
yeah, back in the day when you
would do a daily source code and
things would you came in knowing
what you were getting your your
bad rest on,
Adam Curry: that allows stuff.
Yeah, good to go. Yeah.
Dave Jones: And so this, this,
this evolved at the first, maybe
the first 15 minutes or so 20
minutes, you're kind of like
understanding where this thing
was headed. About 30 minutes
into it, you're hitting the
groove, I'm gonna like it was.
And then and then an hour in,
you were just, I mean, it was
full, it was like it was 2004
all over again. I mean, these
are 2007. I mean, he's been,
you're killing it.
Adam Curry: The thing that was
that was weird is I, you know,
Spotify, the he used to have.
Spotify would allow third party
apps. And you could have two
songs or more even. But you
could have two tracks, one
playing and one queued up. So
while one is playing, you can
then go listen to another one.
But if you only have one,
Spotify app, you can't queue
anything up. So I was literally
like stopping it clicking on
something while I'm talking
clicking on the next one. And
then because it had to load for
a second, you know, the
bandwidth was kind of shitty as
well. So I was really just, you
know, it was very, very low bar
low tech, to do it this way. And
luckily, I had a couple of
tracks myself. So, you know, if
I was trying to queue something
up, I could, you know, do
something else on a different a
pre fader Listen, but it was
definitely not ideal from a,
from a music library standpoint,
it's too bad that Spotify
doesn't allow you to do that
anymore.
Dave Jones: I've never done
obviously never done any of that
kind of thing. So I'm imagining
that the way it goes is your the
the track this live is playing
and then you and then off sort
of offline or off air pre prefix
you okay, you're listening to
the next tried to get up to
figure out what's what is going
to be Yeah, and then you cute.
You're okay. That's how it goes.
Yeah. The fact that you couldn't
do that, and it was still as
smooth as it was. I mean, your
brother?
Adam Curry: Totally. Hey, I'm
also available for bar mitzvahs
and weddings. boosters,
boosters, boosters live. We've
saved yet another life. I'm very
happy to. Very happy. Yeah,
well. I think this person wanted
to stay anonymous. Okay, thanks
for opening my eyes to the pod
fasting side effects, which I
think is called pod speeding.
Because sound pod pod fasting
Dave Jones: sounds like you're
not lucky like you're listening.
Yes, yes.
Adam Curry: So my use case was
this. I tried to listen to the
show live on pod verse. But my
wife is in Germany, but my wife
wouldn't let me listen to the
whole show. So the next morning,
I would one point 25 bit to re
listen to the bits I heard, live
and catch up on the missed out
sections. Of course, this meant
that I'd be fidgety the day
after now I know why. And I
won't do it again.
Dave Jones: Thank you very much
about that. There's a delay.
There's your it takes you a day
to come down.
Adam Curry: Yes. Okay, well, how
about this? So RTP Richard
Peterson, key cop something when
you and I were discussing this,
and it really blew my mind I
have to set it up. So when we
were talking about you know that
this stuff can hijack your
nervous system and makes you
impatient with the people you
around you who you love or nip
the office or your kids. It
conditions you to accept fake
people like that radio GPT lady,
you know, there's a whole bunch
of downsides to it. And you said
that, you know, you had heard me
bitching about this several
years ago. And and you stopped
doing it and you notice that
immediately you or not like a
day or two later you had more
patience, right? Am I my
recounting that correctly?
Dave Jones: Yeah, it took a
couple of days it took two three
days and then I realized that
everything felt more right and
like everything just felt
normal. And like like as far as
listening to the speak because I
was so used to I've been
listening to you guys for years
on fast speed and it took it
took two or three days for me to
get used to not hearing you like
that. But then it's like is as
soon as my mind adjusted to it,
everything else fell into place
to own on like in the world.
Adam Curry: So one of the things
you would use is the silence
chopper. From Yes, so now listen
to that podcast. So this is last
week's board meeting the minute
you start talking about the sped
up chopped silences you actually
start talking fast. Listen to it
as a as a reformed
Dave Jones: podcast, multi multi
multi XOR I don't know what you
call that multispeed person
sick. Yeah. Yeah, as a
Unknown: form, sicko. Yeah,
Dave Jones: I used I used to
listen to All my podcasts in one
at one point I speed up speed up
with the with the whatever
whatever that thing is where
chops out the silences between
them and all that kind of stuff.
Adam Curry: Yeah, the silence
chopper. Did you hear what you
just did there? Yeah, I started
Dave Jones: as I just went, boom
Adam Curry: a little bit. Yeah.
And then and then right after
that you slow down again listen,
listen,
Dave Jones: whatever, whatever
that thing is where chops out
the silences between them and
all that kind of stuff. Yeah,
the silence chopper. Silence Joe
Yeah. And then.
Adam Curry: And then you go back
to normal speed. I think that
it's still in you. The
programming is still there. You
need you need an exorcism, I
believe I believe
Dave Jones: it's a virus
Adam Curry: you're cured, you're
healed. Thank you for that.
Fantastic observation.
Dave Jones: This is a good
observation because I'm
naturally sort of a stammer
because I try to get my brain
goes faster than my mouth. So I
have to get them in sync. And if
I I do this, the way I talk on
the show is exactly the way I
talk to people in all around me
all the time. And I realize that
it frustrates them. And so I
tried to talk slower, but then
if it could, because when I talk
fast, my stammering gets way
worse. It's not stuttering. It's
not like that Nina is not like
that, is because I start a
sentence. Realize it realize
that that's not the right way to
start it and then go back and
sometimes I'll start a sentence
three times in a row. And it
drives Melissa crazy. So like,
the faster I get it becomes just
like it turns into mush.
Adam Curry: Oh, that's
interesting. Well, actually, I
find the way you talk very
engaging I in fact, I enjoy it.
Believe me if I didn't like it,
I would be fuck this thing. I'm
not gonna this board meeting for
two hours. But I enjoy
personally. I like flaws. I like
it when people except the
president, the president, he has
no brains left. I mean, that's
different. What he's what he's
got going on there. But I like
Cridland has also has a stammer.
And it's quite endearing. He is
M's and ELLs. And I like it. I
like that kind of stuff.
Dave Jones: I like the humanity
of it in Yeah. Oh, yeah. It
makes
Adam Curry: you human. It's the
exact opposite of the robo jock.
Dave Jones: That's yeah, that
shakes said nothing wrong.
Adam Curry: Right. There's
nothing wrong, nothing unique.
Nothing interesting. Nothing
that makes you and certainly the
writing was inhumane. I mean,
you know, it's like, this stuff,
in my opinion, all that those
little nuances will never work.
Unless, you know, people start
tricking themselves by listening
to roboticized speech to begin
with, which is what pod speeding
is. Your
Dave Jones: I immediately I
immediately heard the problem
with that. You know, AI bots?
Yeah, the DJ no fake DJ vanilla.
Yeah, it's funny how it like,
have you seen the AR RT stuff?
And it always messes up the
hands? Yes. Like the floors look
like they're look like a bunch
of chopsticks by the way yeah,
that's there's something about
you sound like
Adam Curry: she sounded like
that. But like chopstick
fingers, yeah, sounds like, this
is the value for value podcast.
For those who need an
explanation. We have a whole
website for IT value number four
value dot info. But the whole
concept is, we give you value,
which is free for anyone to
receive. Because of course, we
can charge what we want and make
it set up behind a paywall or
make it to premium content only.
But only you can determine what
something's worth to you. And
maybe a lot of money is 50 cents
or $5 a month or a week or
whatever. And maybe $500 is what
it's worth to you because of
some incredible tip that we gave
you or we made you feel good or
made you laugh or made you feel
human, you get to determine that
and send it back to us. And we
prefer if you do it in a modern
podcast app, podcast apps.com is
where you can find a whole bunch
of someone who had an since we
have so many apps and services
now using the podcast index, and
the API associated with it that
we should probably put the edge
that actually forward you to
podcast index.org/apps We should
probably only put apps there now
and then and make a new section
for all the different hosting
companies and services. Which
probably Yeah, I agree with
Dave Jones: that because you
just like you go to podcast
apps.com And you see Buzzsprout
Adam Curry: Yeah, Is that
someone something anyone can do
with? With a, with a pull
request? That'd be great. That'd
be great. If we can get those
TPS reports done by tomorrow,
that'd be great. Just ask me,
that's real value there. We
would appreciate if someone did
that as value for value that is
valid. valid value.
Dave Jones: The comments, the
cross out comments work on the
website continues. Yeah. And
gourmet. Nathan, John, they're
continuing, you know, they're
just chipping away at this
thing. And I was was going to
get the latest pull request out
today into production, but I
didn't get a chance to but there
I mean, that they're continuing
to do I think they may have
their eyes set on posting, like
feedback like replies.
Adam Curry: Oh, okay. Oh, right.
From the right from the website.
Dave Jones: Yeah, yeah. And so
the changelog podcast guys got
in there. And we're pitching in
to on Oh, cool, awesome stuff.
So yeah, I mean, it's, it's
going somewhere. There's this a
team effort, the website being
open source is fantastic. Number
one, because you don't have the
amount of
Adam Curry: time to time.
Dave Jones: Yeah, you know, it's
funny, it's funny, not being a
JavaScript guy. I learned all
the horrible things about
JavaScript after the fact. So
these are all new to me. Yeah.
And and I say, Oh, my God date
is zero indexed on the month and
everyone's like, Oh, yeah, you
can tell the funding this years
to life,
Adam Curry: as well. So since
you mentioned that, I have, I
have a comment about the
integration of get Alby and
websites. So the experience is
as follows. And I noticed this,
it really hit me when I used pod
verse on the web, the web
version. Here's the experience.
So you have your your wallet
connected, or you're using the
lb extension. So let's take
podcast index.org as an example.
And there's a beautiful box and
you type it all in and you hit
go with the number. And then
I'll be if you're not already
authorized, I'll be able to go
through that process. And then
it pops up and it says, pay this
amount to this person, sit,
create a budget. You know,
always remember, this was all
these options, because it has to
go through the splits, it does
each one independently. And if
you don't know what you're
doing, if you don't say you do
this, then it spits back every
single time. It's like people
you don't know it's very
confusing. And the whole budget
thing it's like, what we need is
an explanation. And the same
goes for when you do it with POD
verse on the web. So get Albie,
because I got a very nice boost
today. But it didn't go through
the splits. And I know why.
Because it was just a user I'd
get Alby and they're using the
extension popped it up curry in
the keeper, boom, and then
whatever else happened that just
dumped out. So we've that has to
be and I understand why from the
get Alby side, I understand, but
that has to be looked at so
maybe Bumi. And the guys can can
take a look at just making it a
little more clear. You know,
what is a budget? Why do I need
a budget? Do I want a budget?
Why do I have to remember this
for the rest? You know, just it
needs? We need some explanation
there. Just some words that
explain to people what's
happening.
Dave Jones: Yeah, I've noticed
that too. And I've kind of
forgotten about it. Yeah.
Adam Curry: I have Trillium.
Dave Jones: Oh, yeah, that thing
you're you're
Adam Curry: organizing. Yes. My
second brain. Exactly. Yeah,
Dave Jones: admit, to bring that
up a few times. Because it runs
you through. It's like, okay,
sand, sand, sand. Sand is it
runs through every one of those.
Yeah,
Adam Curry: and we know what's
happening. But mere mortals and
then we're not talking the
podcast, mere mortals will have
an issue. So that will be
something that that we could
work on.
Dave Jones: Let me throw let me
throw this at you. Maybe at a
left field here or it may not be
I don't know where your where
your minds at but what do you
think about the Spreaker thing
going free? Did you see that?
Yeah.
Adam Curry: I think it's a bit
of a red herring. Because it's
not entirely free. Yes, storage
may be free. But there are still
different tiers. It's kind of a
thing. It's a little bit of a
bait and switch.
Dave Jones: Okay, you may you
sound like you know more about
this than me because I tried to
figure out what they meant and I
couldn't make their press
release make sense. I went
Adam Curry: to the source I went
to the guru Todd Cochran.
Cochran told me now this is bait
and switch, they've got they've
got they still have different
levels and you don't get
everything. It is definitely a
nice offering. To me. It's a
Hail Mary. It's like what are we
going to do now? This is I heart
I believe, right? Do they own
Spreaker?
Dave Jones: Yes, and I've got
So, I would like to dig in on
that, after you say this,
because I've got some, I've got
some art stuff.
Adam Curry: Oh, good. It seems
like some Todd didn't seem
overly concerned about it. I'm
very concerned in general,
because I just don't believe in
free. Because there is no such
thing as free. And you're gonna
get screwed somewhere down the
line. If anything by by getting
the rug pulled from under you, I
don't like it because I know how
much goes into running a good
host and the I don't know much
about Spreaker I believe back in
the early days, Spreaker was
caching the content early, early
days long time, I may be wrong,
but that was Stitcher. I'm
sorry, write your stitches, a
scrap that I know what goes into
making a hosting company work,
especially with customer
service. And I want all of our,
all of the hosting companies to
prosper, and I want them to be
able to, to, you know, to
provide good customer service
and good service in general at a
fair price. And something like
this comes along. And you know,
it's kind of like anchor so it
may also pollute, you know, just
get a lot of pollution out
there, I think is probably to
jack up their numbers. Look how
many podcasts we've got. So I
did I just don't hold them in
high regard for doing this. And
it just doesn't seem like I
mean, I feel and then I'd love
to hear what about the I heart
stuff, I feel personally that
there should be a way for
podcast host to bring people on
at a quid pro quo of value for
value. It's like, we're gonna
take 20% Split until a certain
amount, or whatever, if you want
to pay, you know, you can pay
instead of doing that it's all
enabled right out of the gate.
Something like that, I think
would be a great offering. And I
think that people would pick up
on it. And I think that you'd
probably make more than 20 bucks
a month that you that you do
normally from these podcasts. So
it would be a net win in my
mind.
Dave Jones: Well, that's the
only way I can make this make
sense. And this is before I've
fully understood that it wasn't
free across the board. Because I
was thinking at first I was
thinking, Oh, this is a Charles
Schwab type deal. You know what
I mean? Where they? Schwab was
about three years ago, dropped
their commission fees on trades.
Oh, yeah.
Adam Curry: And everyone
dropped? Yeah, everybody had to
drop it. Yeah.
Dave Jones: And so I thought it
was free across the board. But
this is a little it changes a
little bit. But I still I still
think some of this may apply.
Maybe they are looking out and
they know something ever, I
think, at least on our show me
and you both believe that anchor
isn't going to last forever.
It's going to fold at some
point. It's too much of an
albatross around around Spotify
neck. And that's completely
free. Maybe the the ease of use
of the of the anchor app and all
that stuff was you know, the
thing that made it a train
wreck. I mean, maybe they just
think that their ad dai ad
offering is enough to make up
the difference of all this. You
know,
Adam Curry: what, how about that
maybe? Good point. Maybe they're
thinking, Hey, as long as we get
enough people, jump folks with
with a with a podcast feed will
actually be able to fulfill the
inventory.
Dave Jones: Yeah, that's what
I'm thinking. Yeah,
Adam Curry: that makes sense.
That makes sense.
Dave Jones: Okay, well, that
leads me into this. I brought
some clips. Do you have my
clips? I do. The lets you know,
there was some talk about Marcos
discussion on I guess it was
MacBreak. Weekly, which I did
not watch. Yeah, I didn't watch
it initially. And then I and
then I did and it, you know,
it's fine. I had, I really
didn't have much of a problem
with I think there was some
misunderstanding with chapters.
But other than that, I mean,
basically, Marco at least he
basically just said, I don't
want people telling me what to
do.
Adam Curry: And you know, I hear
you. I don't want people telling
me what to do either.
Dave Jones: I don't either. And
so I'm like, Okay, I mean, I
really wasn't bothered by
anything that he said. But the
more interesting part of their
conversation that was about
advertising, and the display,
Lea one ad market is life
threatening.
Unknown: We're going through I
don't know about you, Marco and
I don't know, we've heard from
other podcasters. We're going
through an advertising downturn
that is existential, it's life
threatening.
Oh, yeah. It's not that bad for
our show. But it's, it's this is
the worst ad market we've seen
in probably a few years. Yeah.
Adam Curry: Yeah. Well, that is
only accentuated by NPR, who say
they have a $30 million deficit
and it's pretty much from the
podcasting department.
Dave Jones: Yeah, not So I think
there's a clearly there's shows
out there that are doing they're
doing just fine. And as the
Independence shows they have
kept their in markets that
they're doing. They're doing
okay. That mean they're not
doing great but they're doing if
I
Adam Curry: may, and I don't
know much about it but but what
I know from the past with AD
markets, if you have a brides
magazine, you're always going to
get DJs venues dressmakers, and
and you know this this was the
PC Magazine, you know, back in
the day, you know, you're gonna
get Dell and HP and everyone's
gonna advertise because it's
just kind of built into their
budget. If you're a general
program, a general podcast, and
you're looking for BMW and and
and T Mobile, etc. Get that's
where you're gonna get cut. So a
specialist tech podcast or we
like a Bitcoin podcast, I'm sure
there may be some some pullback
on the on the overall numbers.
But that's pretty much what
you're, you're still going to
get that it may even involve
more host reads I don't think
that the dynamic inserted ad
market is probably the is really
being affected. But apparently,
even in Leo's network, he says
existential. I think that's
because he just has too many
people too many shows. And as we
all know, you can't you can't
monetize the network. If it's
just twit itself. I'm sure
that's doing fine. I'm sure
security now is doing okay. But
everything else yeah, it may
just be a pullback, because just
too much
Unknown: play Lea to it. This is
normal. This is normal behavior.
And when you're at the bottom of
the down, it might feel like the
world's never going to come
back. But it will eventually.
Good tell that to my AD team.
Okay. Actually, we have a we
have an unusual problem, because
foolishly we built something
that has high overhead. Yeah.
And I mean, we have a two and a
half million dollar a year. Not.
So we don't have the luxury of
saying, well, if advertising,
Stan will just weather it and go
through it. Thank goodness that
we did do that. And I think
everybody who's in podcasting,
for real understands that the
only thing that keeps podcasting
and live as the community, the
listeners, the people who you
have a relationship, direct
relationship with, and clubs,
Patreon, that kind of thing
really give not only give you
that little extra income, but
they make a big difference in
bonding the audience to you. So
we two years ago, we created
club twit, and that was that was
a huge part of it. But it's
still I mean, it's still 1/10 of
1% or something, maybe it's I
would love if I get 5% of the
audience to subscribe, we
wouldn't need advertisers. But
right now it's not even 1% Most
people will getting something
for free aren't gonna start
suddenly paying for it, I'm
afraid.
Adam Curry: I'm afraid you're
wrong. I'm afraid you're wrong.
Dave Jones: You know, clearly
he's wrong. But that that is
that speaks to what you're
saying these in specific shows
are going to do okay, can't
monetize the network. But they
these middle sort of middle
weight columns like a I don't
know the term middle weight
where this kind of like a fat
over hedge, you know, network or
show with those dread ads? Yes,
you're in trouble. Yeah.
Adam Curry: It's also I'm sorry,
podcasting. The only reason it
works. I have one example. Well,
actually, this podcast was a
great example. But it's slightly
different because we have a
project attached to it. So we do
have a specific ask for specific
thing. But without the podcast,
believe me, we wouldn't be
getting anywhere near what we're
what we're getting now. But no
agenda is the example. And you'd
have to keep asking, we ask
everybody we had a newsletter
before the night before the
show. We had the newsletter has
content in it, but we it's
definitely a an ask. The
overhead is incredibly low. And
that is partially because of the
we've we've followed the whole
model all the way through time,
talent, treasure. So voyage zero
mark up in the northern part of
the Netherlands for almost 13
years, maybe longer. He's been
running our infrastructure,
keeping that overhead incredibly
low. Considering the amount of
bandwidth we push. Every website
was built by someone else who
just jumped in to help. And we
acknowledge them and give them
credit for it. And they give him
props. And by the way, they they
sometimes put a little donate
thing on their own work for
that, which we're fine with. So
keeping that this that show was
run out of the vortex top
drawer, basically, you know, I
do all the production stuff. He
handles all the money stuff.
Now, we we of course we have an
accountant and you know, we do
have to pay a little extra and
they're, you know, someone puts
together the spreadsheet. It's
from his family, so we're
getting pretty cheap labor
there. But that's only because
it really grew out of just too
much for us to handle In
addition, but we've kept the
overhead just it's us It's
actually and, again, time
talent, treasure. I have three
four people who reliably,
reliably send me clips that are
perfectly produced and we credit
them for it. In fact, the clip
custodian is in the value for
value split gets a split. He
does, yes. Jeff Smith, who has
created all of our sound imaging
and whenever we say she, we need
jingle for that just miss shows
up. You're not gonna send us a
bill, the art. Now not all of
the audit, we changed the art
for every single show. Not all
the artists have a wallet. I've
encouraged them to get one. The
winning artists whose art is
huge in the show gets a split. I
wish
Dave Jones: people would send
art for our show. Just say.
Adam Curry: Yeah, we'll be fine.
The overhead low is incredibly
important. And this is what
Spotify screwed up.
Dave Jones: Well, this is
affecting I want to I want to
throw a curveball at you in a
second. But I gotta set it up.
Okay, I gotta set it up. And
then I'm gonna I'm gonna
curveball the spit ball at you.
It's gonna be a breaker.
Adam Curry: All right. My bad is
quarks. I'm ready.
Dave Jones: Okay, the. So I
think this is also affecting,
it's affecting the big guys too.
But they've been able to do
something that the middleweight
mass, say the big guys, I mean,
like our heart and the big the
big players, the big ones. So
they have tactics that the small
guys don't have, or the smaller
guys don't have. So this is a
interview on decoder with Conal
Byrne, the CEO of ahart,
digital. And so I heard is split
into sort of two components.
They're split into their digital
audio group and the multi
platform group. The digital
audio group has podcasts, the
multi platform group has
broadcast radio, and in turn,
sort of traditional broadcast.
So play 101, how you hide the
numbers,
Unknown: we felt at I heart that
a lot of the value that we had
as a company, we wanted to
unlock and make more transparent
to the investor community, to
audiences, to researchers to
analysts. One way to do that is
to create different operating
segments in your company so that
you can talk more about how well
you're doing inside certain
divisions and businesses, as
opposed to it all getting lumped
together into one big overall
set of numbers.
Adam Curry: Right, which Spotify
doesn't do very well actually
read.
Dave Jones: They're not very
good. So when I say hide the
numbers, I don't mean that like
they're doing anything
nefarious, because all companies
do this. It's just normal. No,
they're
Adam Curry: just trying to
trying to show the Wall Street.
Dave Jones: Yeah, yeah, this is
this. This is just normal. But
but the smaller, the smaller
groups that can't do this sort
of financial trickery. But the
so if you look at there's a
document in there with the I
heart financials that you may
want to look at, yeah, I got it.
I mean, look at this. I'm
looking at I'm looking at
accountant here. You're like
Adam Curry: a stock guru. This
is like DHL plugged all of a
sudden, okay. I'm looking at a
revenue stream in a table. My
eyes are swimming.
Dave Jones: All right. Yeah. So
the I'm thinking that the
middleweights? Well, let's just
look at our heart thing. So they
said they say on here that they
grew in their, in their podcast
group, they, it says that they
grew 44.3% for the three months
ended December 22. December
2022. Year, in your footnote,
though, correct. In says, it
says this, absent excluding
political revenue, ah, it was
only six and a half percent,
right. It was an election year.
It was an election year and 22.
Adam Curry: Yeah. Which is
billions of dollars billions of
dollars.
Dave Jones: The same thing with
broadcast broadcast that it grew
point 9% in the third quarter
and the fourth quarter, it
actually seemed to exclude
political ad revenue. It was a
loss of 2.8% Yeah, you go in
it's the same thing for the hope
for the full year. The full year
goes from a 22% growth and
podcast revenue to only a 5%.
The
Adam Curry: beauty of political
ads is they don't give a crap
they don't care what you're on
the more crazy you are the
better
Dave Jones: and they blast it
across everything. They let do
like the most broad spectrum by
good catch. So this to me what
what was what was bothering me
or a little weird was why 2022
was a very hard financial
economic year. But the
advertising wasn't as down as
much as you thought it was. A
bit of money came in for the
cause of the political
advertising but then at 23 Now
you're starting to see the pain.
Yeah, like the first quarter of
23 has been brutal. And that
that's where I think that this
may, this may explain Springer's
move here. Because being being
part of I Heart, they may be
feeling feeling the hit. And
they may this may be a push
across the entire company
eventually to go full in dai
dynamic ad insertion. And if
that happens, those done, the
more inventory space you push
onto the market, it's going to
push those CPM rates way down.
Oh, yeah, you're just gonna have
too much, you're gonna have too
much ad space to be filled. And
that's going to affect that's
going to drive everything down
for everybody across the board.
I think this the Latin the fact
that the last year was a
political year and going into
2023. This could be bad, though.
It's
Adam Curry: bad. It's guaranteed
to be bad
Dave Jones: on because everybody
thinks da everybody thinks oh,
listening to leet Leo,
everybody's like, Oh, well
spoke, you know, the baked in
ads, the host reads, those are
struggling right now. But Dai is
where that's okay. But I'm
thinking the AI is about to take
a hit to
Adam Curry: I think it was about
$13 billion spent political
advertising and all medium.
That's a lot of money. It's a
crapload of money. It Yeah. And
but yeah, that's why you know,
all the numbers, you know,
they're down. You know, like,
revenue numbers. What I hear is
like, 23% growth in the first
quarter, and then you know, six.
Dave Jones: Yeah, I think so
this, the Spreaker thing feels
like if they if they actually
have enough people take them up
on up on this offer. And it's
all based on Dai. This could end
up being a pretty bad thing
across the across the industry.
Oh, it's gonna suck. This is
what everybody doesn't
understand that dai the more the
more people you have the sign up
for Dai, the lower the CPMs. Get
for everybody.
Adam Curry: Also. Yeah. And I
think the CPMs of the inserted
ads are quite low. Actually.
They're probably in the 8% 10%.
I'm just spouting because I
don't really know. I did enjoy
something Cridland posted on the
podcast index dot social. It was
a screenshot of some, I guess
tweet and it was a tweet or
remastered on doesn't matter.
Podcasts are the new am talk
radio. Have you heard the ads on
am talk radio, which like
reading your junk folder. And,
and that's true. And you know,
it's ad load really is just, you
know, putting as much in as
possible so they can actually
pay the bills.
Dave Jones: This this Conal
Byrne guy. Yeah, he actually had
this play a heart too, because
he adds something that I think
is relevant to this,
Unknown: there was a moment on
YouTube, where we all sort of
realized the same thing around
like, 2010 or so there's like,
no, the optimal video is this
length, and you have to open
with this kind of thing, and
then close it with that. And to
some extent, you kill creativity
and true innovation when you
start to reverse engineer what
an asset should be for the
content platform that it's going
to be distributed on. In fact,
you almost certainly kill, I
think, true creativity when you
hit that moment. Podcasting,
just as a side questions, not
your question, but as a side
answer to it real quick.
Podcasting has bucked that a
lot. To date. It has resisted
this notion of a podcast episode
is supposed to be 28 minutes
long and have to add brakes.
It's actually a lot of different
kinds of things. It can be a
true crime limited series of
eight to 10 episodes that are 30
minutes long. It can also be
Stuff to Blow Your Mind episode
that sometimes three hours long
of just two guys talking about
stuff. And both are completely
okay, and really perform well,
actually. So it hasn't yet hit
this moment of reverse
engineering from the platforms
that it's on.
Adam Curry: Now, where was this?
It was just part of that
hodgepodge thing. Yeah, it
Dave Jones: was Yeah. Because it
was
Adam Curry: really interesting.
I read a what I thought was a
very honest rundown from the
Hollywood Reporter. And it
really explained, you know, this
hot pod Summit. I'll read just a
couple pieces here from this
article, which to me was like,
you know, the Hollywood Reporter
is going to give you the
Hollywood angle, which means
it's all about the money. That's
it's always all about the money
in various conversation with
studio executives and creators a
common refrain with the
difficulties of turning a profit
on podcasting alone, even
Spotify, which recently
revisited its podcast leadership
again, and had layoffs and show
cancellations in his podcast
division is reevaluating its
spending after pouring more than
$1 billion into licensing deals
with acquisitions in the past
few years. As such, repackaging
audio content and seeking out
derivatives like film and TV
adaptations could be the key to
actually making good money in
podcasting, especially now that
the mega deals of recent years
are getting rare. And podcasters
are feeling the pressure to seek
out more ad dollars from bigger
buyers to keep the lights on
long term. And all of this isn't
even to acknowledge the creative
ambitions around podcasting,
where creators want to produce
expensive, Buzzy narrative
projects that can have a
tangible impact on policy or
public conversation, but may
have a harder time receiving
funding and support compared to
the more assured success of
cheaper always on chat shows.
And this is where a lot of stuff
has gone wrong. You know, the,
in fact, I think the short form
or you know, the limited Ron
eight episode, true crime,
fabulous format, but you just
got to have a couple of really
good people who get together and
do this as almost as a theater
troupe. You know, someone's got
to be able to do the editing,
you've all got to be in it for,
you know, for the love of what
you're doing. Because there's
just not enough money to go
around to be funding these
projects, which from what the
Hollywood Reporter is saying are
basically pilots is basically a
pile. And I know that Dana
Brunetti, who was a you know,
big no agenda guy. And he also
got he got very interested in
podcasting 2.0 with the
transcripts and chapter
features. He did 50 Shades of
Grey, and was the producer on
House of Cards, top notch guy,
top notch guy. And he he's, I
want to do a podcast network. I
said, No, you don't. But okay,
so I want to do a podcast
network. Basically, it's all
scripts, it's all pilots, it's
all pitches. And of course, it
became a very expensive
proposition because people are
now trying to make audio dramas
out of them. And there's really
only room for a few and a few
that will be will be big hits,
and it just is limited and who
can do that stuff. And all the
other podcasts, it's just like
blogging. When that started, I'm
gonna be a millionaire. I'm
gonna be the next Joe Rogan.
It's just it's not that simple.
Dave Jones: I'm glad you brought
that up, because this this is
the perfect time for me to say
dai you suck. I mean, like it is
Dai is, and this is the part of
Adam Curry: dynamic add insert
insertions. Yet
Dave Jones: this, it needs. This
feels like shouting in the wind.
But it needs to stop stop
sucking before it ruins
everything. The part of what
Marco was saying on there was
about chapters was that the
dynamic ad insertion messes up
the timing on chapters. Right
and the so if you look at the
tray, if you look at the
namespace, you've got
transcripts, chapters and
soundbites, the out of let's see
20 to 20 out of 20 tags in the
namespace. Three of them can be
affected by dynamic by lousy
dynamic ad insertion. So if, if
we think about dynamic ad
insertion for what it it will,
first of all chapters can be
done and transcripts and sound
bites, all three can be done and
take dynamic ad insertion into
account. Perfectly fine.
Buzzsprout does it right now.
All of their time spent stamps
are modified when the ads go in.
Yeah,
Adam Curry: bus bras, the only
one I think that really pays
attention to that.
Dave Jones: That is it can be
done if you if you care about
it. End to End soup to nuts to
make this thing to make it stay
consistent. Dynamic ad insertion
into your audio that results in
screwing up the timing of your
other metadata points is like
inserting dynamic banner ads
into your website which randomly
screw up your CSS and change the
way your website layout
Adam Curry: tortured,
hallelujah.
Dave Jones: This is what we're
going to run into. We would not
tolerate that on the web. We
would not tolerate an ad coming
in dynamically and changing the
entire look and feel of the
website or the or all the sudden
making the web making the font
bigger.
Adam Curry: We tolerate so much.
I mean, just the other day I was
listening to pod news weekly
review and it just cuts in the
comments. Session, let's take a
break tu tu tu tu tu. And then
it comes back in and I forgot
what they were talking about. It
was brutal,
Dave Jones: brutal. If you let a
dynamic ad insertion, blow up
your website layout, you've
chosen easy money over and over
content quality. In that, that
is the the problem here. The
point of podcasting is audio. If
you let a dynamic ad provider,
just blow up your audio and and
your feed and make your fan
screw that it is a poor
experience all the way around. I
mean, I, in some ways, I don't
Adam Curry: say we should not
allow.
Dave Jones: I agree Satan, I
think you're exactly right. We
should not allow this is that
wasn't appropriate voice for
what Dai is
Adam Curry: the evil. Evil is a
tool of Satan show title.
Dave Jones: It is a tool of
Beelzebub. And that should be
it's a darkness a dark tool.
Yeah, and here's what's gonna
happen. Everybody's everybody's
dar implementations that went in
with no care about any of the
supporting structure, like the
trap chapters, transcripts, all
this because it is going to end
result in things being screwed
up from here on out. And then
the DA market is going to tank
when everybody floods in to try
and do dir because host raids
aren't making any money. The
CPMs are going to go down and
we're going to end up with punch
the monkey banner ads. In audio,
Adam Curry: I forgot all about
punch the monkey. That's what's
gonna happen once the monkey and
whack a mole. Remember that rock
and roll?
Dave Jones: You're gonna have
the equivalent that is what
we're going to be left with this
disgusting audio as
Adam Curry: well. Honestly, when
it comes to the ad market, we're
still basically counting hips. I
mean, yeah, it's all bullshit.
It's not without any it's not
real IAB is is bullshit,
bullshit numbers. I mean, I love
that's why I love op three, op
three, at least it's open,
everyone can see what it is. You
can agree you can disagree. But
it's all the same for everybody.
Now, but when you get all these
different ways of counting and
not counting and who cares? A
download or listen, time spent
list? I got all those steps. I
got all the time spent
completion rate. Yeah, my
completion rate here at home was
100%. Let me know. I mean, I'm
just telling you.
Dave Jones: I think you mean
it's a whole five
Adam Curry: by five.
Dave Jones: Oh, no cat
Adam Curry: and all counts,
baby. Exactly. Yeah, I feel bad
about it. But I understand
because there was such a hype.
Certainly in the last couple of
years, so much free money. So
much. D E is going into
podcasting. Cuz that's what the
you know, all that money's dried
up. Now. Notice there's no more
Africa podcast day and, and
bipoc podcast day, that's all
starting to fade away because
the money is kind of drying up.
Now.
Dave Jones: Right?
Adam Curry: mean, it just seems
to me that, you know, money in
money out I mean, it, there's
just less of it. And it was a
lot of people were riding high
on the hog. The podcast
Industrial Complex was there.
And now you know, you get
YouTube saying they'll do
something or soft toss or toss
away stuff. They don't really
care.
Dave Jones: They really don't do
things like inclusion
initiatives when you have lots
of money. Yeah, but then, you
know, but then when you have,
when you're cutting, even the
people you have, that you see
how important those things
actually are to people. Because
they, you know, they're like,
Oh, well, you know, we got to
let you know, we don't care that
much. We get this money thing,
you know?
Adam Curry: Yeah, it's like,
they're not even they don't even
talk to Cridland. I mean, we
want to do anything in podcast
and you gotta at least talk to
Cridland,
Dave Jones: we care enough and
we care a whole bunch until it
affects the stock price. And
then we don't care about
Adam Curry: the exact the people
that care for the podcasters is
right here in this group. People
who care the ones that podcast
index dot social, they actually
care. Now, I still truly believe
the reason why this project is
working is because everybody has
a shot at at a cut of the money
flow. Everybody's got a chance
at and everybody can include
themselves. I really believe
that that's a big part of the of
the of the of the I mean that
it's exciting to me every day. I
wake up
Dave Jones: go ahead with value
for value. All that matters is
the is the quality of the
content. Yeah, yeah. If you make
a good product, you get value.
That's there's no other. There's
no other secret sauce. You don't
you
Adam Curry: don't have to buy
adds in games that you know that
start auto downloading or
convince people to click on
stuff now you're absolutely
right. And I get great
statistics. Speaking of which,
by the way,
Dave Jones: you have statistics.
Yeah, I
Adam Curry: got lots of stats,
contracts, contracts CLN, sh a x
dot app, it is doing something
very interesting. I wanted to
pitch this to other people who
listen to this podcast. So they
are statistics company, I guess
their company was really, it's
really just an app. And that app
loads in your browser that it's
without a server, I think,
almost server lists. And all
your stats are loaded up and
they run in your browser. And I
think they're doing with that
with web assembly, that was not
the way what it is web assembly.
And so they said, hey, you know,
we want to, we want to be a part
of the flow. So can we have
access to the podcaster wallet,
which we had done previously for
fountain? And you don't have to
tell me who else who else. So
you can actually stream Satoshis
rather the first ones. So
contracts is now actively out
there. Marketing to podcasters,
Hey, come on in, look at all the
stats we'll give you give you a
wallet, we sign you up, we make
you value for value enabled. And
and you can manage your splits
right here. And we're a
statistics provider. And of
course, they I don't know
exactly what they take, but you
know, but they've they have, you
know, the wallet can wherever
they are getting Satoshi
somewhere in the flow. I want to
pitch to anybody who wants to do
this, we have what I think is
called a Partner API. Some
special access anything you even
if you just want to be an
onboarding partner, you know,
you can you can do a deal with
Alby or possibly with breeze
coming up or you know, or
voltage or, and there's so many
different people you can do a
deal with a pot with with
wallets. Or maybe your wallet
provider I don't know. Or maybe
you just do a an arm's length
deal and connect people into get
Alby doesn't matter, you can
onboard people into value for
value and get a piece of the
action for doing that. And I
really want to encourage people
to think about doing that. It's
a great way to move value for
value forward when we're growing
at about 100 new podcasts a day.
Dave Jones: That brings up
that's that actually makes me
want to bring up Daniel J.
Lewis, his comment about the
fees?
Adam Curry: Yes, please. Well,
Dave Jones: I think I mean, it's
not it's not too much to get
into. But I think that, here's
the way that I look at the My
reasoning for lightning based
value for value is really
simple. It's undie, platform
mobile. If that's a word,
Adam Curry: we prefer to say
censorship resistant,
Dave Jones: it's okay. Also
known as on D platform,
Adam Curry: let me just write
that down another show title.
Dave Jones: No middlemen, the
payment goes from directly from
the listener directly to you.
There's nobody in between. And
the fees are small, very tiny
networks, you run it yourself.
But in order 123, those are the
way those are the order of
importance that I see those that
correct. The higher fees that he
is talking about, all come from
add on services. So if if I
haven't, if I if I run a number
on myself list, I'm just going
to give a scenario. If I run an
umbrella in my house, and I also
run a podcast zone, those
lightning value value payments
coming from the listener to me,
the fees are virtually non
existent. Correct, they're very,
very small, way less than
anything else you can get. Now,
if I have a custodial wallet
somewhere, let's just say with
blueberry, or Alby or some other
place that okay that they're
going to take a percentage
because you've given you're now
using their service and also you
add on a cot, you know,
contracts for staff. But
there's, you know, you're you're
now using somebody else's sir,
all these serve all these fees,
they're coming from additional
services that people are
offering, but those aren't, but
at the low of this, that's the
difference is at the at the most
fundamental level, in the
lightening value for value
ecosystem. I can run it myself
and avoid all that. Yes. But in
the other system, the Patreon
the the you know, these other
papers, you can't you don't even
have that option. You were
excluded in the Fiat world from
from participating in that
whatsoever in
Adam Curry: addition, so that I
think a good example. And now
apps will charge what apps want
to charge. And I, and it's
unfortunate but the fee, label,
you know, the network fee, for
actually transferring a payment
is not the same as a fee that is
taken by an app or a service,
yet, they're both called a fee.
Voila, it is what it is. But if
you take the plugin, the pod
press plug in, I think it is
power press. So there's a 3%
fee, they tack on for that. If
you don't like it, it's a free
market. It's a free market, you
can you can go to some other
servers who do it for less.
Same, we were saying with
podcast apps, if a podcast app
is charging 5%, and your
listeners don't like it, your
listeners can use a different
app, you can recommend a
different app. This is this is
the open market this is you
know, and it's we're already
getting close to having enough
competition out there that it
will naturally kind of drive the
prices down. It's beautiful that
way. And ultimately, as you
point out, you can have an
umbrella at home on your cable
modem. And wherever, wherever
you want to host host your
files. And you can keep that
really within your own realm,
which is the beauty of
podcasting. And you'll still be
listed right up there with all
the big boys and podcasts. Next,
it comes out of the same API.
Dave Jones: In the end, there's
an M M, I'm not saying that
everybody can run an umbrella.
I'm, that's not at all what I'm
saying. I'm saying in this in
this framework in this scenario,
you you could if you wanted to,
if you wanted to go learn it,
and you or if you have the the
ability, or if you know somebody
that can help you, you can do it
yourself. In the other world you
can't. That's that is to me that
is the fundamental difference of
what's better everything else.
Everything else is just sort of
like gravy on top of that,
Adam Curry: including the the
fact that micro payments
themselves are just not feasible
in any other system. In a Fiat
Fiat world is just not possible.
Right. Right. We're so smart.
Dave Jones: That's the same
thing. You know, do you see red
circle started popping? No, I
didn't cool. Yes. Yeah. They
started they started and there's
so he might Kayden over at Red
Circle started the pod pain flow
a couple of days ago, and he's
easy said he's got about 13,000
feets he thinks Wow. Fantastic.
Yes. So that's coming on board.
We've got there's somebody
there's another host, a larger
host that is about to start
popping in that I cannot reveal
yet.
Adam Curry: Oh, Todd Cochran,
all of a sudden, I just, I
can't. I had a very interesting
conversation. I can't talk. You
can't say it yet. Don't worry.
It's coming. In the crowning.
Sorry, sorry, sorry. Sorry.
Dave Jones: I like to just say,
give a heads up, even though I'm
being coy. I like to give a
heads up because I'd like I like
people to hear that things are
happening. So they, they realize
that they're the things move
slow, you know, things in the in
open source projects. Prior and
then podcasting, especially
things move slow. So I like to
let people know that there is
momentum and things are
happening and don't get
discouraged. Even even because
they're going oh, this
Adam Curry: is so much
happening. I mean, I have to say
especially blueberry, big props.
I listened to their podcast
insider, all about namespace all
about the new features, that
Todd has seen the writing on the
wall, them and I really
appreciate that about him. He's
just gone. I know, everything's
flat. So we got to go, you know,
everyone's zigging, you ever
we're gonna zag. We'll go over
and do this. And he's really
pushing and he's educating. And
he's, he's doing it himself. Now
he's, he's eating the dog food,
which is important. It's really
important. And, you know, this
is the difference between making
bold, especially value for value
work, is by following you know,
the general guidelines, the
general format of explaining
value, you want value back,
there's a feedback loop, you got
to thank people. You know, you
got to do it consistently. And
for my money, you should also be
mentioning the amount of
Satoshis that you're receiving.
Because it first of all, is very
transparent. People love that.
It's also very aspirational. And
we've seen that ourselves. Like,
just with that live thing we did
with the dance party. If I
didn't tell people to request I
didn't tell people to boost 5000
SATs more for each song. I
didn't come up with that. But I
accepted it.
Dave Jones: As you're breaking,
you're breaking the rules based
podcasting order.
Adam Curry: This international
international rules of
podcasting rules based order.
Dave Jones: Yeah, exactly. In
the in the internet in the
international rules based
podcasting order. We're like
North Korea.
Adam Curry: Yeah, we're lobbing
missiles everywhere. There does
Dave Jones: that. Fancy Japan
mostly. They were in the air at
one point.
Adam Curry: I just want to do a
couple of quick boosts that
we've been receiving since since
starting Dred Scott who of
course we love 33,333 He wants a
birthday shout out. Well, of
course. Happy birthday. Happy
birthday drab. I think was his
panties that were left on the
turntable yesterday. I'm
Dave Jones: not quite sure. Hey,
now Hey,
Adam Curry: thank you to phone
boy. Cuz I I did interrupt his
show, or we interrupted his show
on the stream. 6969 sent that
twice. Actually. He said never
thought I'd be a lead in for the
pod father on a Saturday,
Phoenix and I appreciate all
you're doing to advance
podcasting. Come experience the
Lotus effect for yourself at
oops, at Lotus effect dot show.
And thank you very much for
letting us letting us break in
like that. We just shot in here
sir Spencer 16969 Thanks again.
Dave. For the wonderful time
Sunday. I'm bowls with buds.
Thanks, Adam for the club 30
throwback in the rowdy boardroom
dance party. Yes, anyone can run
an unbroken, not everyone is
willing but for minimal effort.
Everyone is capable. I think
that's actually kind of true.
They do minimum, a man's just as
much to learn how to set up a
podcast is to set that up.
Dave Jones: People set up a
stereo system. That's not easy,
either. I remember
Adam Curry: those days. You got
to strip the wires for the
speaker connectors.
Dave Jones: Yeah. And your mom
would always call you and ask
you wouldn't How do you turn it
on? You
Adam Curry: turn it off? Are you
connected properly? Watch cable.
Okay, let's see. Well, we'll do
more, we'll do more boost in a
second.
Dave Jones: Added enclosure. So
dad was working with Dan
Benjamin on a on a project of
his and he needed he needed a
way to
Adam Curry: are you an advisor?
Dave Jones: Yes, yeah. I'm an
8am, an unpaid adviser. The the
API, he needed a way to call the
API and say, Okay, I've got an
iTunes ID and an enclosure URL.
I don't know any other way to
reach outside. He's like I got I
want. I know the enclosure URL
of the episode I need to get.
And I know the iTunes ID of the
feed. So I given those two
things. I want to be able to
give them to the index to the
API and have in Have you
returned the show the episode.
So we did that. So that's
interesting. That's in there
now. So if you have if you hit a
scenario where you're like, I
don't know the episode GUID, or
any other the title or really
anything else about the episode,
all I know is the enclosure URL.
You can now submit you can now
add that on as an extra
parameter to the episodes by
iTunes ID your episodes by feed
ID endpoints. And it will give
you back the correct episode
information.
Adam Curry: Okay. Yes, that
sounds like a cool endpoint.
Dave Jones: That's pretty neat.
We hang in
Adam Curry: that all night. Oh,
episode.
Dave Jones: We were moving
forward then. The API.
Adam Curry: Good. pretty rich,
getting pretty rich there, Dave?
Dave Jones: stuff with it? Yeah,
you can do a lot of stuff with
it. I don't think I even talked
about on the show that you can
now get live items back from the
episodes endpoint. So if you
call the episodes by feed ID
endpoint to give it a feed ID or
a feed URL. It will hand you
back the episodes and the live
items. If if the show is live,
has live out of scheduled or
live currently, you will get
those back to there's there's a
lot of stuff that I only post
about, like when we change the
API. I'm only posting about it
on podcast index dot social, and
I forget to talk about it on the
show.
Adam Curry: No, this was good.
There was something else I saw
on the GitHub. An author tag you
were talking about. I think just
some So you're
Dave Jones: ready to talk about
publisher?
Adam Curry: Publisher? Yeah.
Publisher author. Yes.
Dave Jones: So there's a
proposal for a tag. This is
namespace talk. You want to drop
that? Oh,
Adam Curry: I'm sorry. We
haven't done that in quite a
while. And now it's time for
some hot namespace talk. Yeah,
so I heard the dance party last
night. Yeah. Jennifer came right
in, man. She's like, she's
partying down.
Dave Jones: It is 730. On
Saturday. Nice. I mean, that's
appropriate.
Adam Curry: It's okay. For now.
Yeah.
Dave Jones: So that there was a
proposal for a publisher, a way
to track publishers of shows
instead of just simply the, the,
the host of the show. So if you
have, like a way to for you to
go in and say, Okay, I want to
see all of the podcasts by I
don't know what at wondery or
luminary, or NPR just made NPR,
NPR is NPR. Some of them are
tagged correctly, or tagged in a
way that you can do that some of
them aren't. If there was a tag
there that was specifically for
that. In the so he gives the
reference of the iTunes author
tag, which is supposed to kind
of be that way. But it's, it's a
little too freeform. And so the
freeform of the of it. Again,
not a word, but the free form 80
of it is a little problematic,
because you can't it gets messy.
Is it? You know, if you have to,
if you have two publishers,
let's just say it's a joint
effort between the New York
Times and cereal Yeah. Are you
just gonna have freeform text in
their New York Times and cereal?
And then another one may say
cereal a New York Times? No,
that's
Adam Curry: not that's not
that's not structured data
Dave Jones: is not structured
data. So he proposed a way to do
it by, you know, will in a more
structured way where you have
multiple entries there where
it's for each publisher,
enclosed in sort of a parent
tag. And then you can ease more
easily aggregate that and then
go back after the fact and say,
show me all the podcasts by the
New York Times and you get them
all. Together. think there needs
more comments on that though?
Adam Curry: Okay. I have a link
to it in the in the show notes.
Dave Jones: Because I'm a little
I think it's not. It needs that
it. I see what he's doing. And I
like it, but it does need some
work. And I think there just
needs to be more voices in there
commenting on it would be good.
Also in the namespace. On that
side of things, let's see what
actually didn't me. I didn't
have another namespace you get
anything else I get find this?
Adam Curry: Yes. I wanted to
give another plug for the
transcript search tool, which
Steven B put together. He needs
a domain name right now. It's
transcript das search dot versal
dot app. Not a great name. No,
but it's it's how we started
everything off. And he uses that
kind of as his building place.
This thing is outstanding. And
I'm not sure how to integrate it
into public life. I use it all
the time. I mean, you literally
type in A C podcasting. 2.0 and
you can search the directory,
that was my request. Okay, there
it is podcasting. 2.0. And then
you can say Alright, now I'm
going to do a search term. So
let's give me a search term.
That's crazy. Dave, what's
something that we could use in
our
Dave Jones: show?
Adam Curry: Yeah, in our show,
yeah. Something that's gonna
show up once or twice.
Dave Jones: Just only once or
twice. Oh my gosh. Okay, cake.
See, aka Jenkins
Adam Curry: Well turns out
episode 118 one occurrence, and
I can click on the timecode and
then I can hit play these things
that was just icing on the cake
for a corporation to score
brownie points. Oh, come on.
That's pretty rad. Episode 100
streamers and dreamers 158 17
Unknown: craft services table
eating cake and drinking
Prosecco.
Adam Curry: Even got it from
from a clip. This is good.
Dave Jones: That is red. is rad.
Correct? Yeah,
Adam Curry: let's see if RAD is
in there. Let's see rad. Rad.
Seems like there's a lot in
there. Also picks up rod Do you
know the traditional way maybe
if I do it in quotes, I wonder
how well that search is. Let me
see. Yeah, nothing when I do it
and in quotes nothing. How about
radio and now it doesn't,
doesn't do the Boolean
unfortunate Ellie just says it's
beautiful something something
needs to be done with this tool
other than just, I use it. I use
it all the time, particularly
when divorce acts as a dad. Now
I can just go Yeah, you did. And
I boom, click click, you saw a
fast I did that.
Dave Jones: That's really very
Adam Curry: impressive is very,
very impressive. And firstly, it
needs a domain names to even be
first of all these domain name.
It's just it's it's fantastic.
It's a great tool.
Dave Jones: I found Okay, so I
found this the so we have we
have phase six here. And we've
got a few tags, I think we need
to start to coalesce around what
what we think is going to get to
has a chance to make it in
there.
Adam Curry: Okay, what was the
Dave Jones: list? There is?
Value see the secret message.
There's the state tag, which I'm
sure Daniel has a comment about
the name of that. The state tag
is just some way to identify
where weather this some things
about this feed that don't
really fit into other
categories. So things like is it
free? Is it premium? That kind
of that kind of thing? As it is
a paid for feed? Let's see what
the let's see what I've got in
there already. Yeah, so is it?
Is it true? Is this under a
trial? Is the podcast on hiatus?
Is it a subscription only? Is
it? Is it an under a trial
period by the published by the
hosting platform, sort of some
stuff about the feed that you
might want to know. But it's you
could group them together. And
this may not be a great way to
do it. I'm just I just threw
this out there for comment, then
you have John Spurlock's events.
Adam Curry: Yes, yes. Yes. Yes.
Well, that really needs some
work the events tag.
Dave Jones: It's got a lot of
commentary on it right here.
Okay. And, and I feel like we
need to start trying to decide
whether or not that can actually
get get refined to in a way that
everybody's happy with to get
into Phase six. The C D has
guests, James grillin. proposed
a tag. There's just a simple
Boolean tag. Patek podcast co
lon has guests, yes or no,
right. And it's just, it's just
what it says on the box. A lot
of people seem to like this
idea.
Adam Curry: Yeah, sounds good.
That sounds good to me.
Dave Jones: My first thought
when I saw it was math. And then
like, and then I thought about
it. And I'm like, you know, that
actually is pretty good idea.
There's really not another way
to get that. And a lot of these
tags are about it seems like in
phase six, there's a lot of
stuff around just giving
information that is not, maybe
it's not necessary, it's not
critical to the show. But it's
helpful to have Dara say,
discovery. Like, I can see this
feeding. So these fall under a
category to me of, of bits of
information that you as the
podcaster may want to let other
let the world know. It's it's
not. It's sort of like, like,
like the person tag, or the
location tag, it's it's just, I
can put this into my show, I can
mark this in my show at my
hosting company that gives a
signal to the world about what
they can expect to find in my
show. I found those sorts of
things to be valuable, because,
you know, some people just
don't, they don't like interview
shows. They're just not that
like, it's I'm never gonna
listen to an interview show. I
don't really listen to hardly
any interview shows. I guess
it's just not my thing. And so
if it's a show that has guests,
I'm probably not gonna listen to
it. And I can see that being
just more you know, ways to let
the universe know about what are
the sort of the framework of
what your show is? Again, not
not critical, but helpful. Um,
hold
Adam Curry: on one second. Let
me let me tell you, like, let me
test this.
Dave Jones: My first thought
when I saw it was math
Adam Curry: They go long live
the ISO bought
Dave Jones: the ISO but thought
I said, Man, they thought that
was the most the right way to
say, man.
Adam Curry: Doesn't matter. I'm
still loving it.
Dave Jones: And the remote item
tag, I really think out of the
whole batch, the remote item tag
is the one I want to get in
there the most.
Adam Curry: I'm with you on
that. I like that idea.
Dave Jones: I think if nothing
else, we need to get the remote
item tag in there. Events. To
me, it goes in this order remote
item events. And then there's
list mediums. And I think those
list mediums need to go in there
as well.
Adam Curry: Yeah, yeah, that's a
good one. Because we need we
need. We need a lot. We need
something for that. I'm looking
at the music side project.com.
And the search is just not
music. The search populates with
everything. It doesn't. Yeah,
that's inherently not right. And
I think that, I don't know,
maybe if you just search for any
term in them, that you think
would be music, I get podcast.
Dave Jones: Oh, what if you
search for podcasting today? No,
yeah, you get a podcast. That's
not That's not the way I think
it should be. No, he intended
that.
Adam Curry: Is there a way to
only search for music?
Dave Jones: That I thought
that's what it would do? Yeah.
But
Adam Curry: how do we have an
API endpoint?
Unknown: I thought we did.
Adam Curry: Maybe not. Yikes.
Maybe we do. Here's another
question. Is wavelike Tada. We
Dave Jones: do we do, don't we?
Adam Curry: I don't know. I'm
not in charge of that.
Dave Jones: Wave. Wave like is
not pod pinging? They're not no
Adam Curry: but they but they
are adding stuff to the to the
index.
Dave Jones: Hmm Yeah, well,
we're Yeah, we're picking it up.
Okay. They submit Yeah. That
their Gosh, net now you know
what now I feel caught off guard
because they may be pod paying
me who runs this
Adam Curry: a I don't know who
runs anything who runs the show
here?
Dave Jones: Podcast? No idea.
Wow. I have no idea what
anything. That's good. This is
good. Good question. I'm
literally ever saw Michael ever
wave like a potty.
Adam Curry: That's so funny.
That's so funny.
Dave Jones: I see. No. I see no
pod paying that I've ever sent
to Mike. I think he's just
submitting. All right.
Adam Curry: Because I'm super
pumped. And we're going to have
these guys on pretty soon,
right?
Dave Jones: Yeah, the after we
after we screwed them. After I
screwed them over. We're
Adam Curry: gonna have on
eventually. Right. We'll fix
that. Yeah.
Dave Jones: Okay. Yeah, I am
kind of glad that they did. I
screwed that up. And they didn't
show up.
Adam Curry: And that would have
been even worse. Yeah. Would
have been worse. We had sorry,
by the way we
Dave Jones: understand Adam,
Adam Curry: so I was just Yeah,
right. Well, I switched to a
different a different internet
connection. That worked. Okay.
But the amount of people who
said hey, I'm available, I can
do it like Sam Sethi like hey, I
can do I can jump on right now.
I couldn't do anything that Dave
can do. I'm like, no.
Dave Jones: Let's see how it is.
Sam you can be okay. Exactly.
You know, my back.
Adam Curry: And I'm like, No,
this is not gonna happen. That's
not ever gonna happen. This is
the show.
Dave Jones: Hey, James Sam's
ever ever out of town? Give me a
call
Adam Curry: Yeah, that's what
your for your friends as well.
The duty you read in
Dave Jones: the back. So that's
right.
Adam Curry: You got thanks for
people I do have. I do have
another small item that I'm not
quite sure. I just want to bring
it up. Because, you know, I've
been looking at noster I've been
on noster I have a you know, my
key is there whatever. I go on
from time to time. And I'm
sensing hostility. I don't like
it. And I'll tell you what it
is. It goes like this.
Podcasting to point out value
for value stocks, everything
should be zaps and wishes okay,
because you know, like whatever
people can say whatever they
want, because now this
Dave Jones: thing they you just
said is this a tone that you're
picking up? Or is this something
that was actually said?
Adam Curry: No, it was said it
was said that way? There was
there was a thread? Yeah, I
mean, of course I am
interpreting the actual tone of
voice, which is what I
translated to appropriately.
Yes, yes. And of course, Oscar
over the fountain immediately
makes zapping available I'm on
fountain, to the fountain
wallet. And I'm, I'm just not
feeling good about this. I'm not
sure what it is, other than it
feels like Ellen, Ellen URL
mafia all over again. You know,
like Henry, there was even a
thread like, you know, noster
should replace RSS feeds or
whatever. There's all kinds of
stuff and and I'm just like, I'm
not worried about any of that.
But I want to be able to harness
the the excitement over zaps. If
there's a valid place for that
in, in podcasting value for
value streaming stuff, I just
don't see it. And it's kind of
bugged me.
Dave Jones: I mean, it's been
irritating me too. And it's so
this, I saw the RSS thing.
There's this cult, this,
Adam Curry: who used to use the
C word C word you may use cult?
No.
Dave Jones: Maybe Maybe I
started to say culture. Oh,
cool. Maybe called is a root
word of culture is called. It is
a twofer. I get them both. Yes.
Right. So there's this, there's
this sort of like, I feel like
there's a I've been spending
time on nostra to, to, I need to
understand this thing and what
and what's happening over there?
And what's being said, and I
just want I don't like, don't
like, there being all this
motion. And I don't understand
what's happening.
Adam Curry: Yeah, there you go.
That's exactly it. Yeah, it's
like,
Dave Jones: it's like this, like
a bunch of loud things, driving
by your house, you know, for 15
minutes, eventually, you're
gonna get out and look out the
window. So this spending time to
me, I feel like there is this
culture of the sugar daddy
culture in Austria, and I think
it comes from Dorsey the fact
that that Dorsey is bankrolling
a bunch of stuff over there.
Yeah. Agree. And that that's
where you get this sort of like,
I'm going to pay a bounty of, of
a million sets, if somebody
makes RSS feeds on noster. It's
like, why this is, it's just a
dumb idea. To me, it's the whole
it's the it's just dumb. I mean,
there are, so you're going to
ingest an RSS feed, and then
post it on noster. Like, what is
it? What's the point? And I
don't even know, I just don't
understand this. And we've
already we already went down
this road. That is, I think
people, people in the not in the
Ellen URL nostra group may not
understand that we've already
thought a lot of this stuff
through. Yeah, we've fought the
battle to get some to get this
stuff the way that it operates
now, and that is, you, you it is
not the right solution to force
some to force the listener to
create an invoice every time
they want to pay you. It's key
send is much as much as people
may not like he said it is the
right answer to this problem.
And being able to, and there
should not have to be any name
resolution, that putting a a
node ID into a feed with key
send is the lamest and meanest
solution. And it solves this
problem perfectly. The app
doesn't have to do hardly any
work at all. It just, it just
looks at the node ID and boom,
it's done. You don't have to do
all this crazy Ellen, your LP.
Look at your nip 50 sevens. And
all this guy's like, you got to
do all that. And so that's 10
splits in their feed. I mean,
look at Think about how hard
that is for the app.
Adam Curry: How about this? Is
there a way to make a bridge so
people if they're really want to
send a zap, they can zap a
podcast and it hits the bridge,
and that splits it into keys.
And that's something Brian of
London would build, by the way.
It's one of those Rube Goldberg
things.
Dave Jones: I'm just I'm just
not interested. Okay. I'm not
interested in the, to me. Here's
not noster has a people that I
respect like Alex Gleason have
some interest in noster. And so
I'm not going to say that it's a
pile of crap. But I just feel
like the use cases they're
trying to put it to my opinion
is the the social media use case
was the worst.
Adam Curry: It's probably the
worst one they could have used.
I totally agree.
Dave Jones: It should have been
something it could have should
have come out of the gate with a
different use case. And because
this this thing is just not
compelling to me. I get on my
app And I don't want to be like
Debbie downer, like, beat this
thing down. Because I don't want
people doing that to the early
work of of what we're doing here
either things that we're running
with scissors, they're running
with scissors. I want to be
fair. But it's just I don't see
the point of a lot of this. A
lot of these use cases as the
way they're being implemented
because you have the I get on my
noster app. I mean, I forget
what the Damas and half the time
I've got, I get on there, I
start to scroll my timeline, and
then things begin are popping
up. Like after the fact, like,
there were five seconds
Adam Curry: the relay start to
kick in.
Dave Jones: And then and then I
don't know where I'm at in my
timeline anymore, and no. Okay,
so let's scroll back up to the
top, scroll by start start
again. And then people's names
are showing up as just pub keys
and generic avatars. They're
just permanent that way. And
then, and I tap on, then it does
the name resolution to find out
who they are. It's just not a
great experience
Adam Curry: I'm seeing in the
chat room or head saying no, no,
no, it's easy to do. It took
less than a weekend to add Ellen
Euro fall back. If Kishen fails,
the guys that get Alby are
suggesting it if we need to stop
something, I need you to say it
now. Why exactly is it not? Is
it too too much overhead for
apps to do this.
Dave Jones: So So if if you have
if you have to force breeze to
on a show like ours, which which
has nine splits, if you have to
force breeze, to do an Ellen URL
p resolution nine times every
minute, and boosts on top of
that. That's not That's not just
a lot of a lot of load on the
server. Imagine if you have 100
listeners at all listening to
your podcast at the same time,
which is where we want this
thing to be Yeah, imagine,
imagine no agenda. You have Oh
goodness. 700 people listening
live at the same time. 2000
Adam Curry: Let's make it 2000.
Again,
Dave Jones: let's say 2000
people listening live on breeze.
Every one of those breeze apps
is sending a streaming payment
once a minute and having to do
pretend potentially nine or 10 l
in your LP invoice generations
and look up processes through
nip 57. That's a that's called a
DDoS attack.
Adam Curry: Thank you. That's
exactly that's exactly what it
would be. Yeah, it's just not
both ends. By the way. You'd be
dossing your own app,
Dave Jones: your is too much
overhead. You can't you can't do
that. And the nature of the
streaming payments is is
critical booster great booster
grams are awesome. But the
streaming per minute payments,
that's where the lifeblood of
the future lightening value for
value economy comes from,
because that is how people I
forget to boost it. And I'm
listening to the show. But I
always know that that 100 SATs
minute that I selected, that's
always going to be ping, ping,
ping, ping ping, right. And I
don't have to, I don't have to
remember in people, once a
minute you the podcasters
looking at their dashboard is
Ping, ping ping to get income
coming in. And then also it's
Adam Curry: okay, that's a good
point. People who who want to
integrate and this arrowhead is
not going to stop who thinks
zapping is important, that's
great. But your your fucking
everybody else because you can't
do splits. You're not going to
do that no one's going to be
zapping nine different times and
nine different values. So you're
circumventing the whole process.
And I would I would also
encourage other apps and
services to consider that you're
really undermining it.
Dave Jones: You're podcasting is
not social media. They're
correct.
Adam Curry: And I love zapping
as as a replacement for like I
think that's a great idea. It's
fantastic to I mean, and that's
where it's appropriate. Makes a
lot of and I liked it that it's
getting people into the into the
habit of returning some value
for something I like that a lot.
I really do. But stay in your
lane, because it's an it's not a
we put a lot of work into the
whole infrastructure. And you
know, when I hear the get Alby
and everyone wants to do this, I
think they're riding a train and
they're screwing themselves and
other people with it.
Dave Jones: I agree to and I
think that I fully understand
what you're saying. I think
you're right. The zapping is a
great mechanic for returning
value for a value for value ecos
system in general, it makes
sense. The way that the way that
noster it the social media
aspect of nostrils designed the
zapping makes sense. That's Yes,
podcasting. They're not the
same. keep them separate. This
just doesn't make sense for
podcasting. We've, we've, we've
been through this we've done
this is where two and a half
years into this noster is brand
new. This is not the same thing.
Adam Curry: Yeah, and the main
thing, and this is what I want
to say to our head who's saying
no, it's the same as a boost.
No, it's not. Because we have a
split flow is not the same as a
boost. I'm just I, you know, as
a wallet provider get Alby makes
total sense. They can do
whatever they want, you know,
they want to do Aaron, what is
the what is the API payment
thing? Was LSAT? Yeah, they
there'll be many applications
for LSAT. Absolutely. Fountain,
questionable. So I'm just saying
if you want to break the system
by by having people circumvent
the splits. Have at it, but
you're going to lose out in the
long run in the long run.
Dave Jones: I think there's a
general issue here where this
has always been the word and I
just want to be, I want to step
back and be gracious to
everybody for a minute. I think
there is a a, there's always
been within this project. There
have been Bitcoiners coming to
podcasting and podcasting coming
to Bitcoin. Yeah. And so the
those there's a natural sort of
missing a natural, a natural,
like a Venn diagram. And they
overlap in the middle, but
there's a lot of places they
don't. So there's there's going
to be a natural tendency for one
side to do things one way the
other side to do things the
other way. And in podcasting 2.0
We have to make we have to be in
the middle of that of that Venn
diagram and make those things
mesh. Yeah, because the Bitcoin
people are gonna see things one
way and be like, Yeah, let's do
that. To me, this is the
fundamental mistake of of, of
forcing alien URL. Elon, you RLP
down and down podcasting,
throat, it's not gonna work
we've already thought this
through. So just
Adam Curry: just know that we
have looked at we have looked at
it is not necessarily going to
be a great idea.
Dave Jones: Yeah, and podcasters
also have ideas that don't fit
within the other side. So we
have to mediate that as well. So
yeah, I think I think there's
just a bit especially the bit
the Bitcoin people, because
there's money involved. And what
you see it with these bounties
and that kind of thing, that
they, they just want to run off
and do something and it's like
you guys, you mean you can't,
she's not the way it works. And
you got to slow down and get
some consensus here. And think
about, think about the the
industry and the audience that
you're trying to address with
the technology that you're
making. If you're, if you're
trying to address problems
within podcasting, or music, or
other types of things, you need
to understand that industry
fully before you dive in and
start building something and
trying to propose a standard
standards aren't bad, but you
have to at least understand what
the audience needs before you
make it.
Adam Curry: I guess now, I know
how Marco feels. Right? Because
I really felt like people were
bullying. You know, it's like,
Nah, man, this is the way to go.
This is the way it is right now.
I don't think so.
Dave Jones: Anyway, you know, I
know some people did that to
Marco that I you know, we we
told the people early on to
chill out and stop being that
way. You know, I don't think I
think his problems over those
people not not with yes, no,
Adam Curry: no, no, no, I know
that. I know.
Dave Jones: He made he made a
comment about standards. And you
know, we
Adam Curry: do we have a
standard there's lots of
there's,
Dave Jones: I think those are
gonna be the other thing I said
we we we briefly entertained
calling things standards and
made
Adam Curry: by requests from
from hosting companies, by the
way, it was a request to do
that. And I think we even tried
to I certainly tried to pick
that up and it just died on the
vine. And And honestly, I'm
happy.
Dave Jones: Their specs, these
are these justifications and you
can either do them or not, you
don't nobody's forcing anybody
to do anything.
Adam Curry: Yeah, exactly.
You're all podcasting. 2.0 It's
just more podcasting is not
breaking anything. It's not
changing anything. It's not
making a new standard. And we're
gonna we have some interesting
meeting scheduled with people
who are kind of into that I'm
not sure I would even be for
calling it a standard or W three
C. You know, I love the way
everything works. Now. We're the
boss, and everyone else can
pounce like that. I like that
system I mean it's so far it's
worked out really well it's been
a very open process and it's
been fantastic you know and the
minute you bring you know like
official structure into it I was
like oh that's gonna ruin it
Dave Jones: you can Yeah, that's
right. Oh airhead says landing
addresses are no longer only
Elon URL that's right because
because we booked that system
initially to get key sand in
there as well so that's right I
said I mean this this stuff has
been thought through
Adam Curry: Yeah. Anyway, let's
take a few people as we move
towards a buck 45 here okay, we
got the SIR Spencer stuff we got
blueberry 17,776 Big freedom
boost sending boost pilling
karma. Tonight I will attempt
giving comedian Sam Tripoli the
PC 2.0 equivalent of telling
someone that 911 hijackers were
identified by the passports
found at the base of the Twin
Towers. Okay, sounds great. Oh,
and there's Phoenix. The better
half of a phone boy. Also 6969
SAS Thank you pod father for all
you're doing lady Phoenix and
Lord phone boy the Lowe's
effect. Come for the shenanigans
stay for the party. We really
appreciate you guys letting us
bust in here. Eric P. P 33,333.
About an hour ago Dred Scott
5555 says Adam was really having
fun yesterday was great to
witness. It was great to have
you all there as well. Dred
Scott also, the only guy I'll
check it again, but the only guy
ever to use the tally coin
unchained payment system that we
have so proudly displayed by
request. He did send us let's
see. Holy crap. drab. I see
nuts.
Dave Jones: When did he fall in
the keyboard?
Adam Curry: 224,035. saps
Unknown: sock 20 is blades only
Impala
Adam Curry: shouldn't add to the
tally coin yesterday.
Dave Jones: JB you do too much.
Adam Curry: I really do much.
And we give him we only give him
like a 5% cut on the split for
chapters. Well, I do give it on
every single podcast I do. So
maybe he's able to recycle some
of it. And let's see, chat F
3333. Hey, I only requested Ride
the Lightning after someone
requested milkshake. Yeah,
that's right. That was for you a
special milkshake. Milkshake. So
yes, chat F No. 3333 A Chris,
you know 9013 You can't just go
out there do pole work whenever
you want. You first have to call
up and put in a poll request.
Yeah. Dred Scott boosting Dave's
poll works 5555 your poll work
was outstanding. I've been told
and there's dread with a pre
boost 55,555 or dread.
Dave Jones: I'm gonna start
sending this back. Yeah. Yeah,
Adam Curry: yeah, we got your
and that's another beautiful
thing. We don't need any
permission to send him money.
Dave Jones: That's right. And he
didn't even stop us. That's the
beautiful thing about Kison
Adam Curry: lyceum. Which of
course is Martin Linda's Coke, a
replay of yesterday's Liberty
boost regarding and those 2112
Regarding the song 55 million
Frenchmen. And Benjamin
Bellinis. Post music tip. This
is always so cryptic, happy
music. radio.com. Okay, thank
you very much, Martin. Let's see
what else do I have? I think I
think that's all it is. I know,
you'll of course have all of the
all of the booths from
yesterday, I think I think
pretty much everybody so we can
run through them pretty quick,
because a lot of requests there.
So
Dave Jones: I grabbed the
boosts. I didn't try to get the
boost from today or anything.
I'm just gonna stick and read
the boost that I had prepared
for Friday's show. Yeah, that's
probably good. Because I got
everybody else. Yeah. And then
we'll sort it out later. Yeah.
Well, we had a we had $200 from
Oscar Mary over fountain. Oh,
Unknown: wow. 20 is Blake on am
Paula thank you, Oscar.
Dave Jones: Very kind enough
always to support us monthly.
Appreciate Oscar. Thank you,
brother. And we got some booster
grants. We got 22 to 22 big road
ducks from Todd in Northern
Virginia. Just boosting it to
eggs can't stop won't stop
Adam Curry: don't stop don't
stop
Dave Jones: don't let anybody
make you stop. Don't
Adam Curry: ever ever,
Dave Jones: ever mere mortals
podcast. 2222 Road ducks he says
no secrets between board members
spilled Buzzsprout beans Dave
Buzzsprout being Buzzsprout
Adam Curry: beans. That's about
boost boost boost.
Dave Jones: I didn't know I had
bus route beans
Adam Curry: must have must be
something You alluded to
somewhere
Dave Jones: okay, I don't even
remember I'm sorry. I don't
remember. more memorable
character back again 5555
through found and he says,
Congrats on getting to your
first Bitcoin meetup. Dave,
Texas slim will be at the one
here in Brisbane next week. I'm
super pumped on my birthday as
well. Oh, cool. I'm going to
Brisbane,
Adam Curry: Brisbane, Brisbane,
Brisbane, Brisbane, Brisbane,
Dave Jones: Brisbane, this was
it. Yeah. Whoosh. 12498 the
fountain nappy says bye
podcasting. 2.0x go podcasting
just keep it at the suggested
speed.
Adam Curry: Yeah, we will go
podcast
Dave Jones: close to Texas slim
going all the way down to
Australia for
Adam Curry: he's doing beef
initiative down under. He's
doing the same. He's been really
getting a lot of attention.
Dave Jones: And he's preaching
the gospel. Like to the far
flung reaches of the Earth. It
was a
Adam Curry: pretty cool article
about him and ABC, which is
Australian Broadcasting
Corporation, M M, five M. And
they said, A man who's who's who
goes by Texas limb. And we asked
him for his full name. He said
that's all you need to know tax
asleep. Like you don't need to
know I'm Texas slavers. My Mama
knows me by Texas. flim that's
enough.
Dave Jones: Takes us asleep. But
it
Adam Curry: was interesting to
see because you know, of course
there was Bitcoiners there and
you know, like a typical beef
initiative meetup and talking
about purchasing, you know, the
beef with Bitcoin and what the
Australian media but glommed on
to is, you know, this undertone
up feels a lot like the
sovereign man movement, like no,
no, no, no, no, I did have to do
something negative.
Dave Jones: They always do that.
Yeah. Clark in 25,001 SATs
through fountain switching from
Fiat cookbooks to boosting every
episode up the good work and see
it the next meetup Dave, that's
my buddy.
Adam Curry: Oh, nice. He was at
the Bitcoin meetup
Dave Jones: that we wrote
together that's powered Oh nice.
Adam Curry: You take the flatbed
you don't drive that outside
you're 15 minutes city is that
the
Dave Jones: Yeah, nothing in
Birmingham is 15 That's not even
you can't even do 15 minutes in
so I went from contracts
13579 13 festivity now through
pod versus finally time again to
listen to the podcast and boost
alright, we agree on the
listening speed it somehow feels
wrong to listen faster than 1x
and cut pauses boost believer
Thank you 16 969 From Hey
citizen through pod verse. He
says another great show fellas
when I grow up I want to be just
like you too.
Adam Curry: Oh, oh how you doing
booster just like us.
Dave Jones: So sweet. Mere
Mortals podcast to 2222 from
found through fountain he says
Bitcoin meetup update takes a
slam is awesome. And I need to
analyze some of my food choices.
Also bitcoin is awesome. Go
Bitcoin ing. We so I see. We had
to lead up to the meetup. Yeah.
And then the
Adam Curry: actual meetup
themselves. I think Slim is now
on his way to Thailand.
Dave Jones: Wow. Yeah, this
world tour. Well, he
Adam Curry: he was he intended
to retire to Thailand before he
kind of came out of retirement
to do this beef initiative.
Because Thailand is interesting.
I'm not talking Bangkok.
Although that is that is fun for
some things. But more like Shang
Mei Xiang. I've been to Thailand
in a documentary. They're really
nice, really nice people. A very
just sweet population very
giving very open. They love
their royal family, you know, so
they're, they're very, they're
nationalists. Food is fantastic.
It's cheap, cheap to live there.
It's, I understand you, the Thai
culture is really wonderful.
Dave Jones: I've got a friend of
a friend who lived in Thailand
as a teacher for gosh, seven or
eight years. And every time he
came back to the US, he was
like, Oh, my God, things are so
expensive here. He said it was
very cheap there. Lady said you
could you could have a big meal
with five of your buddies Jen.
You know, it would cost you as
much as like a meal for two here
Adam Curry: unless you go to the
no hands restaurant in Bangkok,
which is a whole nother story.
Okay, you know what, you know
what the no hands restaurant is
so so so the food is in a table
is kind of like it's a round
table. And there's to bench
seats comfortable, you know,
pillows and everything. So you
and your friends sit near the
food and behind you will be your
servant. Who then who then will
get your food prepared and feed
it to you?
Dave Jones: Whoa,
Adam Curry: typically naked. Oh,
it's that kind of it was a long
time ago. But it was a
documentary. Funny enough
Dave Jones: is it sounds like a
plot of a movie is what it
sounds like. Yeah,
Adam Curry: yeah, that's when
you know well if you remember
faces of death they actually
don't remember that the monkey
head sticking out and they chop
the head off and they ate the
brains from the live monkey
remember that?
Dave Jones: Yeah, yeah, that was
VHS tape.
Adam Curry: 15/50 generation VHS
tape. Exactly.
Dave Jones: I was convinced that
was real. Like this is all real
man. This was great Yale, our
buddy yell from Vienna. sent us
155,555 sets
Unknown: Sakala Dias Blaze on am
Paula. Thank you. Thank you.
Dave Jones: He says hey, gents,
thank you for your courage from
Vienna but disgusting native ad
with Austrian finance journaux
Nico jilts. We've got a new 2.0
enabled podcast using substack
fix the money.net with
interviews, prophecy tutorials,
and commentary from the Bitcoin
lobbying world. Thank you both
for your encouragement and
patience in GitHub and Mastodon
mercy and Dunker Nice. Thank you
yo, appreciate it. 6969 from a
citizen to pod verse he says. Do
you think sites like no agenda
social.com will have a way to
receive boost the way Podcasts
can.
Adam Curry: I don't see why.
Well how about zaps?
Dave Jones: daps Yeah, yeah,
that's That's great. There
again. That's that's the thing
zaps find for social media. It's
slow motion. It's it's fine.
Yeah. Not good for podcasts. No.
Yes. Don't don't put boosts into
your into your social. Don't put
yourselves into podcasting.
Matthew says
Adam Curry: I'm with you all add
my two cents right to it.
Dave Jones: Another another 6969
from Hey, citizens, he says a
feature request for the podcast
apps, streaming sets using the
DeVore act multiplier. You
listen at one and a half speed
you stream one and a half.
Adam Curry: I agree with that. I
think that's the way to go. This
is a great idea. Now you're
cooking.
Dave Jones: Yeah, you pay for
it. Yeah, boy logs and it's
100,000 SAS through pod verse.
He says thanks for all your hard
work. I'm showing my partner how
V for V works by sending this
one now. Thank you. Oh, cool.
100,000 sets.
Adam Curry: Wow, you know what
you get for that? Bolo.
Unknown: Sakala 20 is Blaze on I
am Paula
Dave Jones: Ameet to SC 32,023
cents Palindrome there 3202335
vs. Podcasting live from floss
conference in Tel Aviv. A P dot
C A P dot a hammock or H A.
Okay, I'm gonna have to read
this as a website. A P dot h
amakor.org. dot i l go
podcasting.
Adam Curry: Okay, go podcast.
Dave Jones: Thank you. Todd
Cochran. 150,420 sets
Unknown: off 20 is Blaze ohm am
Paula.
Dave Jones: He's you're showing
off now. 50% of what was said on
the last show was seriously deer
in the headlights discuss. What
did we say?
Adam Curry: I don't know all
about about I don't know. That
all he said is not only wrote
Dave Jones: now he says growth
in podcasting is flat as a
pancake. And based on calls.
I've been having podcasting
companies are in trouble. That
said best time ever to be a
podcaster as audience numbers
are growing amongst fewer shows,
but go podcasting?
Adam Curry: Yeah, I'm with you
on that. Okay, when he says mean
when he says flat? I mean,
that's the growth of the
companies I guess.
Dave Jones: I guess. I don't
know. Maybe he just means the
number of the number of new
shows outside of the free.
Adam Curry: Yeah, yeah, that's a
bit yeah. New customers for
podcast hosts. Yeah, yeah. I
mean, you're gonna have churn.
You're gonna have people leaving
you need to get new people in. I
don't know. I always hear
Buzzsprout always has another
5000 people every week.
Dave Jones: Yeah, it must. It
must be. If it's like yeah, I
guess they're tied together. I
mean, you're it's a beautiful
thing. Because you're, there's
that direct your customer,
you're the growth of your
company is the growth of your
customer. There's funny money in
between. Exactly. It's a very
natural thing. Thank you, Todd.
Appreciate it. I don't even
remember what we said at the
beginning of this show, much
less last year.
Adam Curry: We talked about our
own lives of ourselves as usual
as you do on a podcast. Let's
talk about herself.
Dave Jones: lyceum. 1776 He says
Adam and Dave, I listened to
Sophie Tucker singing 50 million
Frenchmen can't be wrong. After
reading Benjamin Bellamy's blog,
yeah,
Adam Curry: like I just read
that one. I think a religious
one we had Yeah, we had that
one.
Dave Jones: Okay, yep. All
right, we got it. Well,
chemistry bloggers.
Adam Curry: I was gonna say I
was waiting for him. Where is
he?
Dave Jones: Dignified, Dave and
abiding Adam. Building a medium
that provides the environment
for humanity to coalesce around
since making broadcasters is no
easy feat if you ever want to
take a load off, after all that
digital heavy lifting, kick back
with the AI doc cooking podcast,
inspired by the best
infotainment purveyors in the
realm and hosted by Kentish rock
and Rolla, Gregory Forman, who
always keeps it three by four,
yo CSB whoosh
Adam Curry: moves. Thank you
CSB. He's always there, man. You
can count on him. He's very
consistent.
Dave Jones: They're getting more
and more complex every time
Adam Curry: now. It's okay.
We'll take it we appreciate we
we appreciate everyone who has
been boosting us now you have
some monthlies before we close
out the segment. Yeah.
Dave Jones: I've got I've got a
Michael Kimmerer and $5.33 I've
got a drip Scott at $15 The
Unstoppable drip Scott Lesley
Martin it $2 Christopher Raymer
$10 Aaron Renaud $5 Pedro gun
calvess $5 Scott Jalbert $12
Chad Pharoah 12 $20.22 Martin
Linda scope $1 and Mark Graham
$1. And that's our group.
Adam Curry: And thank you all so
much for delivering the value.
It is really appreciated,
especially yesterday show but
also everyone who showed up
today and in the chat room that
has been contributing if you
want to support podcasting 2.0
the podcast and of course, the
index, go to podcast index.org.
Scroll down to the bottom you'll
see two red donate buttons. One
is for your Fiat fund coupons
via PayPal, and the other one is
that tally coin that only Dred
Scott uses. But of course we'd
love for you to try a modern
podcast app works with all your
old podcast, no problem, you can
export from Apple export from
any podcast, including overcast
whatever it is, even from one of
the newer podcast apps, you can
try them all. Export your OPML
file or your podcasts, whatever
it's called. It's different per
app, and just import it into the
new one. And you got Presto
Wallah. You've got like a rabbit
out of a hat. You've got all of
your subscriptions right there.
And you can now actually
purchase little bits of Bitcoin
Satoshis in think for apps we
have breeze we have fountain we
have pod verse. What am I
forgetting here? I know I'm
forgetting something. Dave
helped me. What the Where you
can you can buy SATs in Fountain
pod verse. Anything with get
Alby I guess? breeze to freeze?
First one, I'm sure there's a
fourth one you can buy by SATs
right through Moon pay right in
the app? I don't remember that.
I you know, we need to we need
to do Apps page. Yeah, I'm
drawing a blank. I don't think
there's a there's not a fourth.
There's no. There's no step
four.
Dave Jones: I don't know what
you may be. I think I know what
you're talking about. Oh, no, I
think I know what you're talking
about. I don't? Yeah. It's not
out yet.
Adam Curry: What am I talking
about? I mean, I'm not Todd
Cochran. I don't have secrets.
Dave Jones: Because I can't
Well, I can't think of anything
else that is
Adam Curry: it doesn't matter.
Just go ahead and figure it out.
Go to new podcast apps.com and
get some things you can boost us
you can join in the fun clearly.
It's a lot of fun, because you
get your name mentioned a lot in
your in your message read. And
you get to have standing amongst
everybody else in the listening
audience. We appreciate that.
Thank you for your thinking. I'm
not thinking your desire. We've
received exactly zero SATs from
Zion ever. But he raised $6
million. Yeah, there you go.
There you go. That's how it
goes. I wouldn't want that. That
albatross around my neck. No
way. No, not at all. Hi,
brother. 8:14pm. It's been a
late one. I'm going to finish
this up. Get everything out. Get
it going. Roll it out. So
everyone can enjoy that this
evening or tomorrow morning
before no agenda. Just stick it
in, stick it into your into your
Sunday morning. And hopefully
everything stays up where you
are and you don't have to go
back to the office. You're gonna
have a nice day off tomorrow.
Dave Jones: I hope everything
stays up where you are.
Adam Curry: I'm gonna see if
we're gonna get back and keep it
say enough. That's alright
buddy. That'll do it. Thanks for
joining. Is this late night
boardroom meeting where we get a
little punchy. We'll be back
next Friday right here
podcasting 2.0
Unknown: You have been listening
to podcasting 2.0 Visit podcast
index.org For more information
podcast.
Dave Jones: Hey, James Sam's out
of town give me a call.